<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Gmagon Software Official Website - Fast, simple &amp; powerful solutions for everyone.</title>
  <subtitle>Gmagon Software Official Website - Fast, simple &amp; powerful solutions for everyone and more. Visit the site to learn, buy, and get support.</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://gmagon.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-07-03T10:07:06.826Z</updated>
  <id>https://gmagon.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Gmagon Inc</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bitwage Officially Launches UK Bitcoin Payroll Services</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/bitwage-officially-launches-uk-bitcoin-payroll-services/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/bitwage-officially-launches-uk-bitcoin-payroll-services/</id>
    <published>2017-07-03T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-03T10:07:06.826Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/iYzuUvb.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>After expanding services in Europe earlier this year, bitcoin payroll and wage payment service provider Bitwage announced its official launch in the UK on Monday.</p>
<p><em><strong>Also read:</strong></em><a href="https://news.bitcoin.com/bitwage-launches-new-functionality-european-customers/" target="_blank" rel="external"><em>Bitwage Launches New Functionality for European Customers</em></a></p>
<h2 id="Bitwage’s-Official-Launch-in-the-UK"><a href="#Bitwage’s-Official-Launch-in-the-UK" class="headerlink" title="Bitwage’s Official Launch in the UK"></a>Bitwage’s Official Launch in the UK</h2><p><a href="https://www.bitwage.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Bitwage</a><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/BJneqen.png!web" alt="">offers solutions for remote workers to receive wages in a variety of currencies including bitcoin. Using the service, workers can get paid in bitcoin without having to ask each employer to pay in the cryptocurrency or sign up with Bitwage. They simply give the employers Bitwage’s bank account details to receive payments in.</p>
<p>Bitwage claims to have over 13,000 registered workers and have processed over $21.6 million in international wages. Users can invoice employers or clients in the United States (US), United Kingdom (UK), and the European Union (EU). Wages received can be split into any ratio between different bank accounts and bitcoin wallets.</p>
<p>On Monday, the company announced the official launch of their services in the UK, stating:</p>
<p>We are now able to offer workers anywhere in the world the ability to receive wages from companies in the UK through local banking partners. This means that our workers can receive wages through Faster Payments, Bacs, Chaps or Swift into local UK GBP bank accounts.</p>
<h2 id="Bacs-Faster-Payments-and-Chaps-Now-Supported"><a href="#Bacs-Faster-Payments-and-Chaps-Now-Supported" class="headerlink" title="Bacs, Faster Payments, and Chaps Now Supported"></a>Bacs, Faster Payments, and Chaps Now Supported</h2><p>Bitwage founder and president Jonathan Chester told Bitcoin.com that the company has been beta testing this service. He explained that although the ability to receive wages in British pounds (GBP) existed previously, it was not done locally and was never publicly launched. Without local UK partners, the service was not cost-effective. Chester detailed:</p>
<p>Before this, we had a banking partner with GBP correspondent accounts in Ireland that could receive Chaps, but not Faster Payments or Bacs. This was a costly solution for potential clients in the UK, so there was very little usage. We have now been working with these same customers during the beta testing of our new local UK services.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/BbIBrau.png!web" alt="">Chaps is the UK’s same-day high-value payment system, currently used by 26 direct participants including the Bank of England and over 5,000 indirect participants. Payments are transferred over Swift and settled intraday in central bank funds. In 2016 Chap’s volumes reached a record 39 million transactions, worth £75.6 trillion.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/iyy2mu7.png!web" alt="">Bacs is responsible for the clearing and settlement of UK automated payment methods, direct debit and Bacs direct credit. The company processed 6.22 billion transactions to UK bank accounts in 2016, worth £4.8 trillion. Faster Payments is a UK banking initiative which uses the Bacs system to reduce payment times between different banks’ customer accounts from three working days to a few hours. While Chaps focuses on same-day service for high-value transactions, Faster Payments is tailored to the much larger number of smaller payments.</p>
<h2 id="Bitwage’s-Growing-List-of-Services"><a href="#Bitwage’s-Growing-List-of-Services" class="headerlink" title="Bitwage’s Growing List of Services"></a>Bitwage’s Growing List of Services</h2><p>In April, Bitcoin.comreported on Bitwage launching unique IBANs for users receiving wages in the European Union. With Monday’s launch in the UK, <img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/22QFnyf.jpg!web" alt="">employers can pay in US dollars, British pounds, and euros. In addition, Bitwage can accept Canadian dollars, Australian dollars, Swiss Francs, and Japanese yen.</p>
<p>Payouts to the workers are far more diverse and are done on the same or next day. Currencies supported include bitcoin, ether, and litecoin, as well as the US dollar, the euro, the British pound, the Brazilian Real, the Philippine peso, the Mexican peso, the Argentine peso, the Indian rupee, the Vietnamese dong, the Nigerian naira, and the Ukrainian hryvnia.</p>
<p>Would you use Bitwage to receive your wages? Let us know in the comments section below.</p>
<p>Images courtesy of Shutterstock, Chaps, Bacs, Faster Payments, and Bitwage</p>
<p>Need to calculate your bitcoin holdings? Check our <a href="http://tools.bitcoin.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">tools</a> section.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/iqQfqmi" target="_blank" rel="external">https://news.bitcoin.com/bitwage-launches-uk-bitcoin-payroll-services/</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img2.tuicool.com/iYzuUvb.jpg!web&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After expanding services in Europe earlier this year, bitcoin payroll a
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Better Software Design with Clean Architecture</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/better-software-design-with-clean-architecture/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/better-software-design-with-clean-architecture/</id>
    <published>2017-07-03T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-03T10:07:06.811Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/vqIfaeY.png!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Have you ever produced code that:</p>
<ul>
<li>was bug laden</li>
<li>was painful to debug or enhance with new features</li>
<li>was hard/impossible to test without things like a database or web server</li>
<li>had presentation logic mixed with business logic or business logic mixed in with data access logic (sql)</li>
<li>was hard for other developers to understand because it did not clearly express its intent or purpose within the application it was written for</li>
</ul>
<p>I know I have. Over time I learned about the various<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_Patterns" target="_blank" rel="external">Gang of Four</a>patterns and made a conscious effort to keep the<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SOLID_%28object-oriented_design%29" target="_blank" rel="external">SOLID</a>principles running on a background thread in my mind as I wrote code. While these ideas certainly helped mitigate the problems listed above, they didn’t eliminate them. When writing web or desktop software using MVC or MVVM I still found some of the same old symptoms showing up in my projects. Things like business logic leaking into controllers, entity models being used all over the place for different purposes and large regions of the code that had no unit test coverage because they had some sort of direct dependency on a database or http client.</p>
<p>Get notified on new posts</p>
<p>Straight from me, no spam, no bullshit. Frequent, helpful, email-only content.</p>
<h2 id="The-answer"><a href="#The-answer" class="headerlink" title="The answer"></a>The answer</h2><p>One day, a colleague sent around<a href="https://8thlight.com/blog/uncle-bob/2012/08/13/the-clean-architecture.html" target="_blank" rel="external">this link</a>introducing<strong>The Clean Architecture</strong>by Uncle Bob. It resonated with me instantly as it presented a solution for the same problems I was seeing. The best part, there’s nothing mystical or complicated about Clean Architecture - it is a relatively simple and practical architecture template that can be applied to many application domains if you choose to follow just a few of its basic rules.</p>
<h2 id="How-Clean-Architecture-works"><a href="#How-Clean-Architecture-works" class="headerlink" title="How Clean Architecture works"></a>How Clean Architecture works</h2><p>The key rule behind Clean Architecture is:<strong>The Dependency Rule</strong>. The gist of this is simply that dependencies are encapsulated in each “ring” of the architecture model and these dependencies can only point inward.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/U3MBbem.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Clean Architecture keeps details like web frameworks and databases in the outer layers while important business rules and policies are housed in the inner circles and have no knowledge of anything outside of themselves. Considering this, you can start to see how it achieves a very_clean_separation of concerns. By ensuring your business rules and core domain logic in the inner circles are completely devoid of any external dependencies or 3rd party libraries means they must be expressed using pure C# POCO classes which makes testing them much easier.</p>
<p>In fact your business rules simply don’t know anything at all about the outside world.</p>
<p>There are a few other important concepts that I’m going to highlight along the way with an example below but if you’re interested in just the theory please go check out<a href="https://8thlight.com/blog/uncle-bob/2012/08/13/the-clean-architecture.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Uncle Bob’s original post introducing Clean Architecture</a>.</p>
<h3 id="Implementing-the-“Course-Registration”-use-case"><a href="#Implementing-the-“Course-Registration”-use-case" class="headerlink" title="Implementing the “Course Registration” use case"></a>Implementing the “Course Registration” use case</h3><p>Let’s see how this works using a real-world use case. For the folks doing agile scrum, I realize a use case is not the most fashionable way to describe a requirement. But for this post, it’s perfect because I’d like to show how all the details of the use case can be modeled within clean architecture. A user story would simply be too vague.</p>
<p>I’ve typed out the entire use case here for reference so you don’t need to digest the whole thing right now. We’ll cover its aspects below in detail as we walk through implementing it using clean architecture.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left">Title</th>
<th style="text-align:left">Register for courses</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Description</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Student accesses the system and views the courses currently available for him to register. Then he selects the courses and registers for them.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Primary Actor</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Student</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Preconditions</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Student is logged into systemStudent has not previously enrolled or registeredStudent cannot register within 5 days of course start date</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Postconditions</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Student is registered for courses</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Main Success Scenario</td>
<td style="text-align:left">Student selects “Register New Courses” from the menu.System displays list of courses available for registering.Student selects one or more courses he wants to register for.Student clicks “Submit” button.System registers student for the selected courses and displays a confirmation message.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">Extensions</td>
<td style="text-align:left">(2a) No courses are available for this student.System displays error message saying no courses are available, and provides the reason &amp; how to rectify if possible.Student either backs out of this use case, or tries again after rectifying the cause.(5a) Some courses could not be registered.System displays message showing which courses were registered, and which courses were not registered along with a reason for each failure.(5b) None of the courses could be registered.System displays message saying none of the courses could be registered, along with a reason for each failure.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>This is a simple use case allowing a student to register for one or more classes and then returning either a success or error result to notify her of the outcome. We’ll use clean architecture to write this use case in a fashion that meets the goals and avoids the problems I mentioned in the intro.</p>
<h3 id="Creating-the-Entities"><a href="#Creating-the-Entities" class="headerlink" title="Creating the Entities"></a>Creating the Entities</h3><p>Entities are the heart of clean architecture and contain any_enterprise-wide_business rules and logic. Now, you might not be working in the context of an_enterprise_and that’s perfectly fine. If you’re writing a standalone application Uncle Bob suggests simply referring to these as Business Objects. The key is that they contain rules that are not<em>application specific</em>- so basically any global or shareable logic that could be reused in other applications should be encapsulated in an entity.</p>
<p>Inspecting our use case there are 2 entities we need:<code>Student</code>and<code>Course</code>.</p>
<p>Using aTDD approach I wrote a couple of tests and just enough code in the<a href="https://github.com/mmacneil/CleanArchitecture/blob/master/CleanArchitecture.Core/Entities/Student.cs" target="_blank" rel="external">Student entity class</a>to get them passing.</p>
<p>The<code>RegisterForCourse()</code>method implements 2 rules from our use case.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div><div class="line">51</div><div class="line">52</div><div class="line">53</div><div class="line">54</div><div class="line">55</div><div class="line">56</div><div class="line">57</div><div class="line">58</div><div class="line">59</div><div class="line">60</div><div class="line">61</div><div class="line">62</div><div class="line">63</div><div class="line">64</div><div class="line">65</div><div class="line">66</div><div class="line">67</div><div class="line">68</div><div class="line">69</div><div class="line">70</div><div class="line">71</div><div class="line">72</div><div class="line">73</div><div class="line">74</div><div class="line">75</div><div class="line">76</div><div class="line">77</div><div class="line">78</div><div class="line">79</div><div class="line">80</div><div class="line">81</div><div class="line">82</div><div class="line">83</div><div class="line">84</div><div class="line">85</div><div class="line">86</div><div class="line">87</div><div class="line">88</div><div class="line">89</div><div class="line">90</div><div class="line">91</div><div class="line">92</div><div class="line">93</div><div class="line">94</div><div class="line">95</div><div class="line">96</div><div class="line">97</div><div class="line">98</div><div class="line">99</div><div class="line">100</div><div class="line">101</div><div class="line">102</div><div class="line">103</div><div class="line">104</div><div class="line">105</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">class</div><div class="line">Student</div><div class="line"> : </div><div class="line">EntityBase</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">string</div><div class="line"> FirstName &#123; </div><div class="line">get</div><div class="line">; </div><div class="line">set</div><div class="line">; &#125;</div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">string</div><div class="line"> LastName &#123; </div><div class="line">get</div><div class="line">; </div><div class="line">set</div><div class="line">; &#125;</div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line"> IList</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">Course</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> RegisteredCourses &#123; </div><div class="line">get</div><div class="line">; &#125;</div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line"> IList</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">Course</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> EnrolledCourses &#123; </div><div class="line">get</div><div class="line">; </div><div class="line">set</div><div class="line">; &#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">Student</div><div class="line">(</div><div class="line">)</div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">      RegisteredCourses = </div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> List</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">Course</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">();</div><div class="line">      EnrolledCourses = </div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> List</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">Course</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">();</div><div class="line">   &#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">bool</div><div class="line">RegisterForCourse</div><div class="line">(</div><div class="line">Course course</div><div class="line">)</div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">      </div><div class="line">// student has not previously enrolled</div><div class="line">if</div><div class="line"> (EnrolledCourses.Any(ec =</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> ec.Code == course.Code)) </div><div class="line">return</div><div class="line">false</div><div class="line">;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">      </div><div class="line">// registration cannot occur with 5 days of course start date</div><div class="line">if</div><div class="line"> (DateTime.UtcNow </div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> course.StartDate.AddDays(</div><div class="line">-5</div><div class="line">)) </div><div class="line">return</div><div class="line">false</div><div class="line">;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">      RegisteredCourses.Add(course);</div><div class="line">      </div><div class="line">return</div><div class="line">true</div><div class="line">;</div><div class="line">   &#125;</div><div class="line">&#125;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div><div class="line">51</div><div class="line">52</div><div class="line">53</div><div class="line">54</div><div class="line">55</div><div class="line">56</div><div class="line">57</div><div class="line">58</div><div class="line">59</div><div class="line">60</div><div class="line">61</div><div class="line">62</div><div class="line">63</div><div class="line">64</div><div class="line">65</div><div class="line">66</div><div class="line">67</div><div class="line">68</div><div class="line">69</div><div class="line">70</div><div class="line">71</div><div class="line">72</div><div class="line">73</div><div class="line">74</div><div class="line">75</div><div class="line">76</div><div class="line">77</div><div class="line">78</div><div class="line">79</div><div class="line">80</div><div class="line">81</div><div class="line">82</div><div class="line">83</div><div class="line">84</div><div class="line">85</div><div class="line">86</div><div class="line">87</div><div class="line">88</div><div class="line">89</div><div class="line">90</div><div class="line">91</div><div class="line">92</div><div class="line">93</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">[Fact]</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">void</div><div class="line">CannotRegisterForCourseWithin5DaysOfStartDate</div><div class="line">(</div><div class="line">)</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">// arrange</div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> student = </div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> Student();</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> course = </div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> Course &#123; Code = </div><div class="line">&quot;BIOL-1507EL&quot;</div><div class="line">, Name = </div><div class="line">&quot;Biology II&quot;</div><div class="line">, StartDate = DateTime.UtcNow.AddDays(+</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">) &#125;;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">// act</div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> result = student.RegisterForCourse(course);</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">// assert</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  Assert.False(result);</div><div class="line">&#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">[Fact]</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">void</div><div class="line">CannotRegisterForCourseAlreadyEnrolledIn</div><div class="line">(</div><div class="line">)</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">// arrange</div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> student = </div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> Student</div><div class="line">  &#123;</div><div class="line">     EnrolledCourses = </div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> List</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">Course</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">     &#123;</div><div class="line">       </div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> Course &#123; Code = </div><div class="line">&quot;BIOL-1507EL&quot;</div><div class="line">, Name = </div><div class="line">&quot;Biology II&quot;</div><div class="line"> &#125;,</div><div class="line">       </div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> Course &#123; Code = </div><div class="line">&quot;MATH-4067EL&quot;</div><div class="line">, Name = </div><div class="line">&quot;Mathematical Theory of Dynamical Systems, Chaos and Fractals&quot;</div><div class="line"> &#125;</div><div class="line">             &#125;</div><div class="line">     &#125;;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"> </div><div class="line">// act</div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> result = student.RegisterForCourse(</div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> Course &#123; Code = </div><div class="line">&quot;BIOL-1507EL&quot;</div><div class="line"> &#125;);</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"> </div><div class="line">// assert</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"> Assert.False(result);</div><div class="line">&#125;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<h3 id="Use-Cases"><a href="#Use-Cases" class="headerlink" title="Use Cases"></a>Use Cases</h3><p>Moving up from the entities we have the_Use Case_layer. The classes that live here have a few unique features and responsibilities:</p>
<ul>
<li>Contain the<br><em>application specific</em><br>business rules</li>
<li>Encapsulate and implement all of the use cases of the system. A good rule to start with is a class per use case</li>
<li>Orchestrate the flow of data to and from the entities, and can rely on their business rules to achieve the goals of the use case</li>
<li>Have NO dependency and are totally isolated from things like a database, UI or special frameworks</li>
<li>Will almost certainly require refactoring if details of the use case requirements change</li>
</ul>
<p>Use case classes are typically suffixed with the word<strong>Interactor</strong>. Uncle Bob mentions in<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0oGpWmS0aYQ" target="_blank" rel="external">this talk</a>that he considered calling them controllers but assumed this would be too easily confused with MVC so Interactor it is!</p>
<p>Our use case is modelled in<a href="https://github.com/mmacneil/CleanArchitecture/blob/master/CleanArchitecture.Core/UseCases/RequestCourseRegistrationInteractor.cs" target="_blank" rel="external">RequestCourseRegistrationInteractor.cs</a>.</p>
<p>There are a few important aspects of the use case class I’d like to highlight.</p>
<p>First off, it implements the<a href="https://github.com/mmacneil/CleanArchitecture/blob/master/CleanArchitecture.Core/Contracts/IRequestHandler.cs" target="_blank" rel="external">IRequestHandler</a>interface. This interface is an example of the<a href="http://www.dofactory.com/net/mediator-design-pattern" target="_blank" rel="external">mediator pattern</a>which dictates that implementors will work with a certain request and response object in a loosely coupled fashion.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">public </div><div class="line">class</div><div class="line">RequestCourseRegistrationInteractor</div><div class="line"> : </div><div class="line">IRequestHandler</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">CourseRegistrationRequestMessage, </div><div class="line">CourseRegistrationResponseMessage</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">...</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>There is a single<code>TResponse Handle(TRequest message)</code>method defined on the interface which essentially performs_all the work_of our use case. Pretty simple huh?_Handle()_takes a request object as its lone parameter which will typically contain any data passed in from the outer layer (the UI) and returns a response message with both types dictated by the<code>IRequestHandler</code>interface. All of our_application specific_logic for the use case will go into this method.</p>
<p>One key aspect of the request/response messages that flow in and out of use case interactors and across boundaries is that they are simple data structures meaning they contain no special types: ie. entities, or types provided by 3rd party libs etc. - they are pure C# objects.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">class</div><div class="line"> CourseRegistrationRequestMessage : IRequest</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">CourseRegistrationResponseMessage</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">int</div><div class="line"> StudentId &#123; </div><div class="line">get</div><div class="line">; </div><div class="line">private</div><div class="line">set</div><div class="line">; &#125;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line"> List</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">string</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> SelectedCourseCodes &#123; </div><div class="line">get</div><div class="line">; </div><div class="line">private</div><div class="line">set</div><div class="line">; &#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line"> CourseRegistrationRequestMessage(</div><div class="line">int</div><div class="line"> studentId,List</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">string</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> selectedCourseCodes)</div><div class="line">  &#123;</div><div class="line">    StudentId = studentId;</div><div class="line">    SelectedCourseCodes = selectedCourseCodes;</div><div class="line">  &#125;</div><div class="line">&#125;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>The_CourseRegistrationRequest_object consists of only a StudentId and a list of selected course codes selected by the user.</p>
<p>Here’s the full implementation of<a href="https://github.com/mmacneil/CleanArchitecture/blob/master/CleanArchitecture.Core/UseCases/RequestCourseRegistrationInteractor.cs" target="_blank" rel="external">RequestCourseRegistrationInteractor.cs</a></p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div><div class="line">51</div><div class="line">52</div><div class="line">53</div><div class="line">54</div><div class="line">55</div><div class="line">56</div><div class="line">57</div><div class="line">58</div><div class="line">59</div><div class="line">60</div><div class="line">61</div><div class="line">62</div><div class="line">63</div><div class="line">64</div><div class="line">65</div><div class="line">66</div><div class="line">67</div><div class="line">68</div><div class="line">69</div><div class="line">70</div><div class="line">71</div><div class="line">72</div><div class="line">73</div><div class="line">74</div><div class="line">75</div><div class="line">76</div><div class="line">77</div><div class="line">78</div><div class="line">79</div><div class="line">80</div><div class="line">81</div><div class="line">82</div><div class="line">83</div><div class="line">84</div><div class="line">85</div><div class="line">86</div><div class="line">87</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">class</div><div class="line">RequestCourseRegistrationInteractor</div><div class="line"> : </div><div class="line">IRequestHandler</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">CourseRegistrationRequestMessage, CourseRegistrationResponseMessage</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">private</div><div class="line"> readonly IStudentRepository _studentRepository;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">private</div><div class="line"> readonly ICourseRepository _courseRepository;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">private</div><div class="line"> readonly IAuthService _authService;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line"> RequestCourseRegistrationInteractor(IAuthService authService, IStudentRepository studentRepository, ICourseRepository courseRepository)</div><div class="line">  &#123;</div><div class="line">    _authService = authService;</div><div class="line">    _studentRepository = studentRepository;</div><div class="line">    _courseRepository = courseRepository;</div><div class="line">  &#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line"> CourseRegistrationResponseMessage Handle(CourseRegistrationRequestMessage message)</div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">// student must be logged into system</div><div class="line">if</div><div class="line"> (!_authService.IsAuthenticated())</div><div class="line">   &#123;</div><div class="line">     </div><div class="line">return</div><div class="line"> new CourseRegistrationResponseMessage(</div><div class="line">false</div><div class="line">,</div><div class="line">null</div><div class="line">,</div><div class="line">&quot;Operation failed, not authenticated.&quot;</div><div class="line">);</div><div class="line">   &#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">// get the student</div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> student = _studentRepository.GetById(message.StudentId);</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">// save off any failures</div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> errors = new List</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">string</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">();</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">   foreach (</div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> c </div><div class="line">in</div><div class="line"> message.SelectedCourseCodes)</div><div class="line">   &#123;</div><div class="line">     </div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> course = _courseRepository.GetByCode(c);</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">     </div><div class="line">if</div><div class="line"> (!student.RegisterForCourse(course))</div><div class="line">     &#123;</div><div class="line">         errors.Add($</div><div class="line">&quot;unable to register for &#123;course.Code&#125;&quot;</div><div class="line">);</div><div class="line">     &#125;</div><div class="line">   &#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">   _studentRepository.Save(student);</div><div class="line">   </div><div class="line">return</div><div class="line"> new CourseRegistrationResponseMessage(!errors.Any(), errors);</div><div class="line">&#125;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>Note the use of<code>_authService</code>,<code>_studentRepository</code>and<code>_courseRepository</code>. These services are typically referred to as_Gateways_within clean architecture and get injected into the Use Case layer as per the dependency rule. These are the things that deal with the database, rest services or other external agencies and their implementation belongs in the_Interface Adapters_layer. Interactors only know_what_behavior these gateways offer by way of their interface definition. They have no idea_how_they do their work because those details are encapsulated in an outer layer which the Use Cases know nothing about.</p>
<h3 id="Interface-Adapters"><a href="#Interface-Adapters" class="headerlink" title="Interface Adapters"></a>Interface Adapters</h3><p>The purpose of the interface adapter layer is to act as a connector between the business logic in our interactors and our framework-specific code. For example, in an ASP.Net MVC app, this is where the models, views, and controllers live. Gateways like services and repositories are also implemented here.</p>
<p>It is this layer, for example, that will wholly contain the MVC architecture of a GUI. The Presenters, Views, and Controllers all belong in here.</p>
<p>Also in this layer is any other adapter necessary to convert data from some external form, such as an external service, to the internal form used by the use cases and entities.</p>
<p>In this example I’m using a basic console app to consume my use case so this serves as my interface adapter layer. It contains the concrete implementations of the required<a href="https://github.com/mmacneil/CleanArchitecture/tree/master/CleanArchitecture.ConsoleApp/Gateways" target="_blank" rel="external">Gateways</a>and has<a href="https://github.com/mmacneil/CleanArchitecture/tree/master/CleanArchitecture.ConsoleApp/Presentation" target="_blank" rel="external">Presentation</a>logic to format the response from the Use Case into something friendly for the UI.</p>
<p>In the Main() method we can see the usage of calling the use case and presenting the results.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div><div class="line">51</div><div class="line">52</div><div class="line">53</div><div class="line">54</div><div class="line">55</div><div class="line">56</div><div class="line">57</div><div class="line">58</div><div class="line">59</div><div class="line">60</div><div class="line">61</div><div class="line">62</div><div class="line">63</div><div class="line">64</div><div class="line">65</div><div class="line">66</div><div class="line">67</div><div class="line">68</div><div class="line">69</div><div class="line">70</div><div class="line">71</div><div class="line">72</div><div class="line">73</div><div class="line">74</div><div class="line">75</div><div class="line">76</div><div class="line">77</div><div class="line">78</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">//</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">**</div><div class="line">// Here we&apos;re connecting our app framework layer with our Use Case Interactors</div><div class="line">// This would typically go in a Controller Action in an MVC context or ViewModel in MVVM etc.</div><div class="line">//</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">*****</div><div class="line">**</div><div class="line">// 1. instantiate Course Registration Use Case injecting Gateways implemented in this layer</div><div class="line">var courseRegistraionRequestUseCase = new RequestCourseRegistrationInteractor(authService, studentRepository, courseRepository);</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">// 2. create the request message passing with the target student id and a list of selected course codes </div><div class="line">var useCaseRequestMessage = new CourseRegistrationRequestMessage(1, new List</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">string</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> &#123; userInput.ToUpper() &#125;);</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">// 3. call the use case and store the response</div><div class="line">var responseMessage = courseRegistraionRequestUseCase.Handle(useCaseRequestMessage);</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">// 4. use a Presenter to convert the use case response to a user friendly ViewModel</div><div class="line">var courseRegistraionResponsePresenter = new CourseRegistrationRequestResponsePresenter();</div><div class="line">var vm = courseRegistraionResponsePresenter.Handle(responseMessage);</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">Console.Clear();</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">// render results</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">if (vm.Success)</div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">  Console.BackgroundColor = ConsoleColor.DarkGreen;</div><div class="line">  Console.ForegroundColor = ConsoleColor.White;</div><div class="line">&#125;</div><div class="line">else</div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">  Console.BackgroundColor = ConsoleColor.Red;</div><div class="line">  Console.ForegroundColor = ConsoleColor.White;</div><div class="line">&#125;</div><div class="line">Console.WriteLine();</div><div class="line">Console.WriteLine(vm.ResultMessage);</div><div class="line">Console.WriteLine();</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<h4 id="Presentation"><a href="#Presentation" class="headerlink" title="Presentation"></a>Presentation</h4><p>We’d like to show something friendly to the user when we get a response back from the interactor. To accomplish this, I created<a href="https://github.com/mmacneil/CleanArchitecture/blob/master/CleanArchitecture.ConsoleApp/Presentation/CourseRegistrationResponsePresenter.cs" target="_blank" rel="external">CourseRegistrationResponsePresenter</a>which has the single responsibility of converting a_CourseRegistrationResponseMessage_into a<em>CourseRegistrationResponseViewModel</em>. I’ll mention again that the response message and viewmodel are POCO objects containing no special types or data structures, just everyday collection and value types.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div><div class="line">51</div><div class="line">52</div><div class="line">53</div><div class="line">54</div><div class="line">55</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">public</div><div class="line">class</div><div class="line">CourseRegistrationResponsePresenter</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">public</div><div class="line"> CourseRegistrationResponseViewModel </div><div class="line">Handle</div><div class="line">(</div><div class="line">CourseRegistrationResponseMessage responseMessage</div><div class="line">)</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">    </div><div class="line">if</div><div class="line"> (responseMessage.Success)</div><div class="line">    &#123;</div><div class="line">         </div><div class="line">return</div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> CourseRegistrationResponseViewModel(</div><div class="line">true</div><div class="line">,</div><div class="line">&quot;Course registration successful!&quot;</div><div class="line">);</div><div class="line">    &#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">    </div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> sb = </div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> StringBuilder();</div><div class="line">    sb.AppendLine(</div><div class="line">&quot;Failed to register course(s)&quot;</div><div class="line">);</div><div class="line">    </div><div class="line">foreach</div><div class="line"> (</div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> e </div><div class="line">in</div><div class="line"> responseMessage.Errors)</div><div class="line">    &#123;</div><div class="line">       sb.AppendLine(e);</div><div class="line">    &#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">    </div><div class="line">return</div><div class="line">new</div><div class="line"> CourseRegistrationResponseViewModel(</div><div class="line">false</div><div class="line">,sb.ToString());</div><div class="line">  &#125;</div><div class="line">&#125;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<h3 id="Frameworks-and-Drivers"><a href="#Frameworks-and-Drivers" class="headerlink" title="Frameworks and Drivers"></a>Frameworks and Drivers</h3><p>This layer contains tools like databases or frameworks. By default, we don’t write very much code in this layer, but it’s important to clearly state the place and priority that those tools have in the architecture.</p>
<h3 id="Summary"><a href="#Summary" class="headerlink" title="Summary"></a>Summary</h3><p>_Clean Architecture_provides a simple and effective framework for separating the different aspects of our system producing a highly decoupled, testable architecture.</p>
<p>Let’s recap some key benefits:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Use Cases are encapsulated in one place meaning they are <strong>very visible and easier to understand</strong>. Business rules are not scattered all over the place making debugging and modification of the code painful.</p>
</li>
<li><p>The Dependency Rule and use of abstracted Gateways mean the core business logic in our Interactors and Entities is<strong>easily testable</strong>and not hampered by external things like databases and RESTful web services. The lack of 3rd party, feature-laden frameworks in our business logic also means thecode there is only focused on the important rules and policies of our application.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Flexibleand<strong>portable</strong>- because the Use Cases are completely decoupled from any UI or infrastructure it’s easy to do things like switch the database or web framework or even port to an entirely new platform. Our example runs in a console app but it could just as easily work on the web, desktop or a phone.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Like most design decisions there are tradeoffs to be made when considering Clean Architecture. For the benefits I highlighted there are also a few disadvantages:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Your team’s ability to ramp up and effectively apply Clean Architecture. There’s nothing radically complex in here but there certainly is a learning curve and time required to adapt to any new design or architectural style.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Applying Clean Architecture adds some bloat in the form of many separate classes for all the Presenters, Use Case Request/Response dtos, Use Case Interactors, Entities, Gateways etc plus all the test cases :). Not a huge deal but a valid knock on the impact of this approach to the size of your project.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I hope this guide has provided some insight on how Clean Architecture can improve your software design and prevent many of the common pitfalls that hinder projects. Like any pattern, it takes a little familiarity with the concepts and principles before they can be effectively applied. A good exercise to start might be to think of some use cases near and dear to you currently - can you map them out mentally using Clean Architecture? Do you have a sense of the Entities, what the Use Case Interactor might look like, what data needs to flow back and forth in the request and response messages? Running your use cases through these questions can help you get started in modeling them using Clean Architecture.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading!</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/mmacneil/CleanArchitecture/" target="_blank" rel="external">source code</a></p>
<p>Get notified on new posts</p>
<p>Straight from me, no spam, no bullshit. Frequent, helpful, email-only content.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/YBj6ZvE" target="_blank" rel="external">https://fullstackmark.com/post/11/better-software-design-with-clean-architecture</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img1.tuicool.com/vqIfaeY.png!web&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever produced code that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;was bug laden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;w
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Angular 4 News Roundup June</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/angular-4-news-roundup-june/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/angular-4-news-roundup-june/</id>
    <published>2017-07-03T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-03T10:07:06.808Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>WRITTEN BY<a href="https://twitter.com/jsdiaries" target="_blank" rel="external">GARETH DUNNE @JSDIARIES</a></p>
<p>ng-June</p>
<p>June has come and gone and it has brought with it a steady month of Angular 4 news. There is a chance that you could have missed a change to key features or components so I’ve listed some of the main snippets of news that may have passed you by.</p>
<p>Although there isn’t much reading material specifically for<strong>Angular 4</strong>I recommend having a look at<strong>ng-book: The Complete Guide to Angular 4</strong><a href="http://geni.us/LCTQUAa" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<p>Its updated with Angular 4 practices and is one of the few books doing so.</p>
<p>Angular 4.2</p>
<p>The most notable piece of Angular news this month is the release of<strong>Angular 4.2</strong>. This is a small update and will not break your current Angular projects via Semantic Versioning which I covered in a previous posthere.</p>
<p>All changes pertaining to the release are mentioned on the official blog here. So what are main highlights we should take our of this update?</p>
<p>Well, the changes to allow the creation of reusable animations using the<code>animation()</code>function enables our animations to become more modular.</p>
<p>I’ve listed a very similar example as the docs here for reference.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">var fadeAnimation = animation([</div><div class="line">  style(&#123; </div><div class="line">opacity:</div><div class="line">&apos;&#123;&#123; start &#125;&#125;&apos;</div><div class="line"> &#125;),</div><div class="line">  animate(</div><div class="line">&apos;&#123;&#123; time &#125;&#125;&apos;</div><div class="line">,</div><div class="line">    style(&#123; </div><div class="line">opacity:</div><div class="line">&apos;&#123;&#123; end &#125;&#125;&apos;</div><div class="line">))</div><div class="line">], &#123; </div><div class="line">params:</div><div class="line"> &#123; </div><div class="line">time:</div><div class="line">&apos;1000ms&apos;</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">start:</div><div class="line">0</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">end:</div><div class="line">1</div><div class="line"> &#125;&#125;);</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">useAnimation</div><div class="line">(fadeAnimation, &#123;</div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">params</div><div class="line">: &#123;</div><div class="line">    </div><div class="line">time</div><div class="line">: </div><div class="line">&apos;2s&apos;</div><div class="line">,</div><div class="line">    </div><div class="line">start</div><div class="line">: </div><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">,</div><div class="line">    </div><div class="line">end</div><div class="line">: </div><div class="line">0</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  &#125;</div><div class="line">&#125;)</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>As you can see we assign our animations to a variable, specify its animation properties and then invoke it using the<code>useAnimation</code>function</p>
<p>Typescript 2.4</p>
<p>Typescript has also updated to a new release, bringing with it dynamic import expressions as well as Safer callback parameter checking. There could be few posts written about these changes so I’ll let the official blog post do the talking<a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/typescript/2017/06/12/announcing-typescript-2-4-rc/" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<p>I’ll just note that the dynamic imports feature in particular is a fantastic addition in this new release. It allows an even deeper layer of lazy loading and enables Webpack to split your bundles even further to only load a particular asset required in a function.</p>
<p>Angular IO</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/Ar6RRbB.png!web" alt=""></p>
<p>angularIO</p>
<p>In order to coincide with Angular 4 features and benefits, the official<a href="https://angular.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">angular.io</a>website has now been converted to a full scale web application. It is now much faster and has increased its performance significantly.</p>
<p>There is also a satisfying element of practice what you preach and the Angular team have clearly rebuilt the website from the ground up with performance in mind.</p>
<p>It may seems like a minor detail but searching through the documentation has now become a better user experience which I’m sure is appreciated throughout the Angular community especially for those browsing on mobile devices.</p>
<p>These were the main notable Angular events and features this month. The framework is progressively evolving every month and if theres enough newsworthy item in July I’ll be sure to do a similar roundup.</p>
<p>Still looking to upgrade your AngularJS app to Angular 2? Check out this tutorial by Toptal<a href="https://www.toptal.com/angular-js/angular-2-upgrading-from-1-5" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/JNZ3qeb" target="_blank" rel="external">http://jsdiaries.com/2017/07/03/angular-4-news-roundup-june/</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;WRITTEN BY&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jsdiaries&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;GARETH DUNNE @JSDIARIES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ng-June&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June h
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A New Way to Reuse DataWeave Functions and Variables in Mule Flows</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/a-new-way-to-reuse-dataweave-functions-and-variables-in-mule-flows/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/a-new-way-to-reuse-dataweave-functions-and-variables-in-mule-flows/</id>
    <published>2017-07-03T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-03T10:07:06.804Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A New Dataweave Function Makes It Easier for You to Store, Reuse, and Share Dataweave Functions Between Flows and Mule Applications.</p>
<h2 id="Reusing-Dataweave-Code"><a href="#Reusing-Dataweave-Code" class="headerlink" title="Reusing Dataweave Code"></a>Reusing Dataweave Code</h2><p><a href="http://www.mulesoft.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">MuleSoft’s</a><a href="https://docs.mulesoft.com/mule-user-guide/v/3.8/dataweave" target="_blank" rel="external">DataWeave</a>technology is a powerful and efficient way to transform complex structured data between popular data formats, including JSON, XML, CSV, and Java objects.</p>
<p>I’m a courseware developer and trainer at<a href="http://www.mulesoft.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">MuleSoft</a>, and recently I’ve been spending a lot of time learning about DataWeave.</p>
<p>In the<a href="https://docs.mulesoft.com/mule-user-guide/v/3.8/dataweave" target="_blank" rel="external">DataWeave</a>1.x version included in the Mule runtime v3.8, there has been limited support for reusing DataWeave functions and variables between Transform Message components (the component that applies DataWeave code). In particular, there is currently no direct support for importing modules or libraries of DataWeave code. But starting with Mule Runtime v3.8.4 there is a new<code>readUrl</code>function you can now use to start reusing DataWeave code across applications and even across deployments.</p>
<p>In this post, you’ll learn how to use the new<code>readUrl</code>function to separate out reusable DataWeave code, and then reuse that code between multiple Transform Message components and flows, including flows in separate applications and MUnit flows. This is a nice new tool to add to your DataWeave tool box.</p>
<h2 id="Creating-a-Mule-Project-With-Reusable-Dataweave-Library-Files"><a href="#Creating-a-Mule-Project-With-Reusable-Dataweave-Library-Files" class="headerlink" title="Creating a Mule Project With Reusable Dataweave Library Files"></a>Creating a Mule Project With Reusable Dataweave Library Files</h2><p>An example Mule project is available in this<a href="https://github.com/ethanport/dataweave-reuse" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub repository</a>. You can import this project into the latest Anypoint Studio to follow along with this post. Alternatively, you can create a new Mule project in Anypoint Studio and copy the examples from this blog post.</p>
<p>This project has added a folder named<code>dw</code>to<code>src/main/resources</code>, and then created a file named<code>myLib.wev</code>inside the<code>dw</code>folder. When this Mule project is exported as a deployable archive file, all the files in<code>src/main/resources</code>will be automatically added to the project’s classes folder, so will be in the classpath when the Mule application is deployed to a Mule runtime. In this sample project, the HTTP listener is listening for requests on port 8081.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/niUVRva.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="Coding-the-Reusable-Dataweave-File"><a href="#Coding-the-Reusable-Dataweave-File" class="headerlink" title="Coding the Reusable Dataweave File"></a>Coding the Reusable Dataweave File</h2><p>The myLib.wev file contains some reusable variables and functions.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">%dw 1.0</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">//Reusable constant</div><div class="line">%var exchangeRateFromUSDToBritishPounds = 1.35</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%function convertPriceFromUSDToBritishPounds ( input )</div><div class="line">//Can </div><div class="line">use</div><div class="line"> the getIntroString() </div><div class="line">function</div><div class="line"> which </div><div class="line">is</div><div class="line"> defined further down</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&quot;$(getIntroString()) :  $(input * exchangeRateFromUSDToBritishPounds)&quot;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%</div><div class="line">function</div><div class="line"> getIntroString()</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&quot;The price converted to British Pounds is&quot;</div><div class="line">---</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">//Provide </div><div class="line">external</div><div class="line">names</div><div class="line">for</div><div class="line">variables</div><div class="line">and</div><div class="line"> functions defined </div><div class="line">in</div><div class="line"> the header</div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">  exchangeRate : exchangeRateFromUSDToBritishPounds,</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  convertPrice : convertPriceFromUSDToBritishPounds,</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  //</div><div class="line">Use</div><div class="line"> an anonymous lambda </div><div class="line">to</div><div class="line">define</div><div class="line"> the </div><div class="line">function</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  formatString : (aString, formatter) -</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> formatter(aString)</div><div class="line">&#125;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>The body expression creates key names for the variables and functions. The<code>exchangeRate</code>key has as value the variable<code>exchangeRateFromUSDToBritishPounds</code>. This variable acts as a constant in other DataWeave functions.</p>
<p>The<code>convertPrice</code>key references the more lengthy function name<code>convertPriceFromUSDToBritishPounds</code>. This function requires a parameter, which is used in the function’s expression to print out the String returned from the later<code>getIntroString()</code>function, plus the result of multiplying the<code>input</code>value by the<code>exchangeRateFromUSDToBritishPounds</code>variable.</p>
<p>The<code>formatString</code>key is different from the other two keys in the body expression. The<code>formatString</code>key has a value which is an anonymous function implementation. These types of unnamed functions are also called lambdas. The lambda requires two input parameters. The first parameter labeled<code>aString</code>is supplied to the<code>formatString</code>function with any string value, which then has the<code>formatter</code>function applied to<code>aString</code>.</p>
<p>Next, you will see how to use these functions, including<code>formatString</code>, in a DataWeave flow.</p>
<h2 id="Reading-in-and-Using-an-External-Dataweave-File"><a href="#Reading-in-and-Using-an-External-Dataweave-File" class="headerlink" title="Reading in and Using an External Dataweave File"></a>Reading in and Using an External Dataweave File</h2><p>The next step is to read in this external DataWeave file and use it in a Transform Message component. The first step is to use the new readUrl function to read in the DataWeave function from the classpath. Define a variable<code>myLib</code>as a reference to the DataWeave file<code>myLib.wev</code>.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">%dw</div><div class="line">1.0</div><div class="line">%output</div><div class="line"> application/json</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%var</div><div class="line"> myLib = readUrl(</div><div class="line">&quot;classpath://dw/myLib.wev&quot;</div><div class="line">)</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>In this example, we are embedding the DataWeave library file inside the project, so we give the URL relative to the classpath<code>dw/myLib.wev</code>. If you are deploying into a customer-hosted on-prem Mule runtime, you could also store your DataWeave libraries in a common external location that you add to the Mule runtime’s classpath.</p>
<p>Note: This is a similar technique to the way you can store Mule application properties files in an external location. You can learn more about this technique in the Anypoint<a href="https://docs.mulesoft.com/mule-user-guide/v/3.8/configuring-properties" target="_blank" rel="external">product documentation</a>, or<a href="https://wrapper.tanukisoftware.com/doc/english/props-envvars.html#definition" target="_blank" rel="external">Tanuki Java Service Wrapper</a>documentation.</p>
<p>Like the related read() function, readUrl() can also include a second parameter to specify the mime type, such as<code>application/java</code>,<code>application/json</code>,<code>application/csv</code>, or<code>application/xml</code>. When not specified, the default mime type is<code>application/dw</code>. So in this example, we could also have written:</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">%dw</div><div class="line">1.0</div><div class="line">%output</div><div class="line"> application/json</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%var</div><div class="line"> myLib = readUrl(</div><div class="line">&quot;classpath://dw/myLib.wev&quot;</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">&quot;application/dw&quot;</div><div class="line">)</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>In Anypoint Studio, the file is stored in<code>src/main/resources</code>, but in the deployable archive, all the files from the<code>src/main/resources</code>folder are moved into the<code>classes</code>folder.</p>
<p>Here is a complete Transform Message component in the convertPrice flow:</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div><div class="line">51</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">%dw </div><div class="line">1.0</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%output application/json</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%</div><div class="line">var</div><div class="line"> myLib = readUrl(</div><div class="line">&quot;classpath://dw/myLib.wev&quot;</div><div class="line">)</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">//Access functions in the myLib reference</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%</div><div class="line">function</div><div class="line">printPrice</div><div class="line">(priceInUSD)</div><div class="line">myLib</div><div class="line">.</div><div class="line">formatString</div><div class="line">( myLib.convertPrice</div><div class="line">(priceInUSD)</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">(price)</div><div class="line"> -</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> upper price )</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">---</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#123; </div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">//Format the key</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  ( </div><div class="line">    myLib.formatString( </div><div class="line">&quot;result&quot;</div><div class="line">, (aString) -</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> capitalize aString ) </div><div class="line">  ) : </div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  </div><div class="line">//Format the value - read in the input price as an HTTP query param</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  printPrice( inboundProperties.</div><div class="line">&apos;http.query.params&apos;</div><div class="line">.price )</div><div class="line">&#125;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<h2 id="Previewing-and-Testing-Dataweave-Code-That-Uses-External-Dataweave-Library-Files"><a href="#Previewing-and-Testing-Dataweave-Code-That-Uses-External-Dataweave-Library-Files" class="headerlink" title="Previewing and Testing Dataweave Code That Uses External Dataweave Library Files"></a>Previewing and Testing Dataweave Code That Uses External Dataweave Library Files</h2><p>You can preview example data transformations using the Preview pane in the Transform Message component editor. In the Transform Message component, in the left-side Input pane, right click on Inbound Properties &gt; http.query.params.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/bUNrIrV.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Set an example price:</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">%dw </div><div class="line">1.0</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%output application/java</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">---</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">price:</div><div class="line">600</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#125;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>In the right-side Output pane, select the Preview button, which opens the Preview pane. In the Preview pane, you should see the result of the body expression.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/E73UZrU.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Change the price from 600 to 500 and verify the output in the Preview pane also changes. This shows you that you can preview live changes to DataWeave code, even when you are reading in external DataWeave files.</p>
<p>Here is the entire<strong>reuseDataWeaveCode.</strong>xmlfile<strong>:</strong></p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div><div class="line">51</div><div class="line">52</div><div class="line">53</div><div class="line">54</div><div class="line">55</div><div class="line">56</div><div class="line">57</div><div class="line">58</div><div class="line">59</div><div class="line">60</div><div class="line">61</div><div class="line">62</div><div class="line">63</div><div class="line">64</div><div class="line">65</div><div class="line">66</div><div class="line">67</div><div class="line">68</div><div class="line">69</div><div class="line">70</div><div class="line">71</div><div class="line">72</div><div class="line">73</div><div class="line">74</div><div class="line">75</div><div class="line">76</div><div class="line">77</div><div class="line">78</div><div class="line">79</div><div class="line">80</div><div class="line">81</div><div class="line">82</div><div class="line">83</div><div class="line">84</div><div class="line">85</div><div class="line">86</div><div class="line">87</div><div class="line">88</div><div class="line">89</div><div class="line">90</div><div class="line">91</div><div class="line">92</div><div class="line">93</div><div class="line">94</div><div class="line">95</div><div class="line">96</div><div class="line">97</div><div class="line">98</div><div class="line">99</div><div class="line">100</div><div class="line">101</div><div class="line">102</div><div class="line">103</div><div class="line">104</div><div class="line">105</div><div class="line">106</div><div class="line">107</div><div class="line">108</div><div class="line">109</div><div class="line">110</div><div class="line">111</div><div class="line">112</div><div class="line">113</div><div class="line">114</div><div class="line">115</div><div class="line">116</div><div class="line">117</div><div class="line">118</div><div class="line">119</div><div class="line">120</div><div class="line">121</div><div class="line">122</div><div class="line">123</div><div class="line">124</div><div class="line">125</div><div class="line">126</div><div class="line">127</div><div class="line">128</div><div class="line">129</div><div class="line">130</div><div class="line">131</div><div class="line">132</div><div class="line">133</div><div class="line">134</div><div class="line">135</div><div class="line">136</div><div class="line">137</div><div class="line">138</div><div class="line">139</div><div class="line">140</div><div class="line">141</div><div class="line">142</div><div class="line">143</div><div class="line">144</div><div class="line">145</div><div class="line">146</div><div class="line">147</div><div class="line">148</div><div class="line">149</div><div class="line">150</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">?</div><div class="line">xml version=</div><div class="line">&quot;1.0&quot;</div><div class="line"> encoding=</div><div class="line">&quot;UTF-8&quot;</div><div class="line">?</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">mule</div><div class="line">xmlns:tracking</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/ee/tracking&quot;</div><div class="line">xmlns:dw</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/ee/dw&quot;</div><div class="line">xmlns:http</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/http&quot;</div><div class="line">xmlns</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/core&quot;</div><div class="line">xmlns:doc</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/documentation&quot;</div><div class="line">xmlns:spring</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;http://www.springframework.org/schema/beans&quot;</div><div class="line">xmlns:xsi</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance&quot;</div><div class="line">xsi:schemaLocation</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;http://www.springframework.org/schema/beans http://www.springframework.org/schema/beans/spring-beans-current.xsd</div><div class="line">http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/core http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/core/current/mule.xsd</div><div class="line">http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/ee/dw http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/ee/dw/current/dw.xsd</div><div class="line">http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/http http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/http/current/mule-http.xsd</div><div class="line">http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/ee/tracking http://www.mulesoft.org/schema/mule/ee/tracking/current/mule-tracking-ee.xsd&quot;</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">http:listener-config</div><div class="line">name</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;HTTP_Listener_Configuration&quot;</div><div class="line">host</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;0.0.0.0&quot;</div><div class="line">port</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;8081&quot;</div><div class="line">doc:name</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;HTTP Listener Configuration&quot;</div><div class="line"> /</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">flow</div><div class="line">name</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;convertPrice&quot;</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">http:listener</div><div class="line">config-ref</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;HTTP_Listener_Configuration&quot;</div><div class="line">path</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;/&quot;</div><div class="line">doc:name</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;HTTP&quot;</div><div class="line"> /</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">dw:transform-message</div><div class="line">doc:name</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;Transform Message&quot;</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">dw:input-inbound-property</div><div class="line">doc:sample</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;sample_data/map_string_string.dwl&quot;</div><div class="line">propertyName</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;http.query.params&quot;</div><div class="line"> /</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">dw:set-payload</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">![CDATA[%dw 1.0</div><div class="line">%var myLib = readUrl(&quot;classpath://dw/myLib.wev&quot;)</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%output application/json</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%function printPrice(priceInUSD)</div><div class="line">myLib.formatString( myLib.convertPrice(priceInUSD), (price) -</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> upper price )</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">%function headerString ()</div><div class="line">&quot;the price2&quot;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">---</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">&#123; </div><div class="line">  //format the key</div><div class="line">  (myLib.formatString( &quot;result&quot;, (aString) -</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line"> capitalize aString )) : </div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">  //Read in the input price as an HTTP query param</div><div class="line">  printPrice(inboundProperties.&apos;http.query.params&apos;.price)</div><div class="line">&#125;</div><div class="line">]]</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">/</div><div class="line">dw:set-payload</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">/</div><div class="line">dw:transform-message</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">logger</div><div class="line">level</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;INFO&quot;</div><div class="line">doc:name</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;Logger&quot;</div><div class="line">message</div><div class="line">=</div><div class="line">&quot;#[message.payload]&quot;</div><div class="line"> /</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">/</div><div class="line">flow</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">&lt;</div><div class="line">/</div><div class="line">mule</div><div class="line">&gt;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<h2 id="Deploying-and-Testing-the-Application"><a href="#Deploying-and-Testing-the-Application" class="headerlink" title="Deploying and Testing the Application"></a>Deploying and Testing the Application</h2><p>Deploy the reuseDataWeaveCode project to a Mule runtime. For example, here I am deploying the project to an Anypoint Platform account from Anypoint Studio.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/YBJFRvF.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>In this example, I deployed the application to a public Anypoint Platform URL<a href="http://reuse-dataweave-code.cloudhub.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">http://reuse-dataweave-code.cloudhub.io</a>.</p>
<p>After the application deploys, open a web client (you can use a web browser), and make a GET request to the HTTP listener. If you deployed to a Mule runtime on your local machine, the URL is<code>http://localhost:8081?price=300</code>. For my CloudHub deployment, I’ll make requests from a web client to<code>http://reuse-dataweave-code.cloudhub.io/?price=700</code>. You can click this URL now to try it out.</p>
<p>My web browser has a JSON parser extension and shows this response:</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/iiyY7rj.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>As you build up more complex DataWeave transformation for your projects, you’ll want to reuse some of your transformation logic. Today, you can do this using the readUrl() function. Please let us know what you think of this feature, and also let us know what additional modularity you’d like to see in future releases.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/bYBzUbZ" target="_blank" rel="external">https://dzone.com/articles/reusing-dataweave-functions-and-variable-in-mule-f</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;A New Dataweave Function Makes It Easier for You to Store, Reuse, and Share Dataweave Functions Between Flows and Mule Applications.&lt;/p&gt;

    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Beware the cutting edge of web design</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/beware-the-cutting-edge-of-web-design/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/07/03/beware-the-cutting-edge-of-web-design/</id>
    <published>2017-07-03T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-03T10:07:06.815Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Progress in web design techniques shows no signs of slowing up. As the proponents of the early web are staggering around with thousand-yard stares, you can’t help but feel a little over-awed by the plethora of techniques and frameworks available nowadays.</p>
<p>People are championing the new approaches that are about to change the way we work once again, such asFlexbox andCSS Grid. Rachel Andrew and Jen Simmons have been encouraging developers to look at these technologies now, in readiness for their arrival.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/BzuUvm2.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Is web design too formulaic, or cutting edge, these days?</p>
<p>Recently, some of the current web industry’s founders – such as Andy Clarke and Jeffrey Zeldman – have asked if it really needs to be this complicated, and whether the web is losing its soul or becoming reliant on a standard output (three-column layouts, hero blocks and the like). Have we all become enslaved to the frameworks and tools available to us?</p>
<p>Although they make a good argument, I don’t think there has been a time where there has been more choice (or opinion) about how to build digital projects. We are long past ‘HTML,CSS and a littleJavaScript’. Now there are CSS preprocessors andJS frameworks, and the components that make up a web project encompass a load of new elements – optimisation, CDN delivery andSEO, to name a few.</p>
<p>An urge to jump into new methods too early can be the worst thing to do on live client work</p>
<p>Sush Kelly</p>
<h3 id="Pioneering-web-tech"><a href="#Pioneering-web-tech" class="headerlink" title="Pioneering web tech"></a>Pioneering web tech</h3><p>The talks and conferences advocate best practices and cutting-edge tech – why we should be using X, Y and Z. This is 100 per cent necessary. After all, the web industry is relatively young and we are still defining the standards of the industry to an extent.</p>
<p>The problem is, those not using these technologies day-to-day in their work can be left feeling inadequate or somehow lacking. It is a lucky few who get to make their living pushing those boundaries and telling us all about them. Don’t get me wrong, it is essential to have these people pushing the bleeding edge, but it can result in an urge to jump into new methods too early, which can be the worst thing to do on live client work.</p>
<p>You want long, productive relationships with clients. Changing how you build sites means having to readjust and remember more skills. As much as good commenting and a README file will help, you need to make sure what you’re delivering will remain effective and usable for as long as possible.</p>
<p>As a digital director at a small creative agency,<a href="https://www.imaginate.uk.com/home" target="_blank" rel="external">Imaginate</a>, it is on my shoulders to make sure we use the right technology on client work and invest our time wisely with regards to what we learn and (in due course) adapt into our processes.</p>
<p>I completely understand how designers and developers want to adopt the next great thing. I feel the same compulsion, and it is actually one of the things that has kept me in the industry so long (since 2000). The fact is that I also have to think about the longevity of the plugin/library/software, because if it doesn’t stand the test of time, or it ends up failing or losing support due to a later development, then the responsibility falls on us.</p>
<h3 id="Educating-junior-web-developers"><a href="#Educating-junior-web-developers" class="headerlink" title="Educating junior web developers"></a>Educating junior web developers</h3><p>Many junior developers have a real thirst for knowledge. It is often an inspiration to more senior team members when they arrive in the studio, eager to show a new method or technique that is emerging and explore how it might be used on a project.</p>
<p>You want your staff to grow, to develop and to be able to work on things together, so again it’s important to make sure that you’re only taking on board advancements that are an improvement on what went before. But when the churn of technology is so quick that we have interns and junior designers who have never had to use a float and do not know life before Bootstrap, it becomes a real balancing act.</p>
<p>A good example of this is the move from LESS to SCSS and also from Grunt to Gulp. Both these technologies are similar, but different enough to mean returning to a project using LESS/Grunt becomes an exercise in re-learning – or in the case of juniors or interns, learning a new (old) technology from scratch.</p>
<h3 id="Website-layout-gambles"><a href="#Website-layout-gambles" class="headerlink" title="Website layout gambles"></a>Website layout gambles</h3><p>Flex and CSS Grids are the current darlings of frontend talk. CSS Grid has the potential to revolutionise the way we will lay websites out in the future. At the moment it is still hidden in the latest browsers, although you can access it if you enable experimental features on the likes of Chrome. We can’t use it in live work for this reason, though with an imminent launch date, Grid could bring about as big a shift in web development practice as the shift from tables to divs and floats.</p>
<p>We are using Flexbox on live work now, but only in ways that are a benefit – for example for ordering content in responsive layouts orvertically centring items. To try to use Flexbox for a full site at the moment, with iOS and Safari’s flaky support, would be a challenge that just may not be financially viable. </p>
<h3 id="Embracing-the-old-browsers"><a href="#Embracing-the-old-browsers" class="headerlink" title="Embracing the old browsers"></a>Embracing the old browsers</h3><p>Clients, especially within larger companies, likely won’t be running the latest browsers. They could also have restrictions on their web access that could affect your build. And if it turns out the main stakeholder is using IE on an old laptop, the site better work on it or the project just won’t get signed off.</p>
<p>Sometimes a client will have a good idea of what they want, or specify an incumbent system or technology that you need to work with. A key point for us as an agency is to be adaptive to these needs and to work with them, rather than dismissing what the client has and trying to force them down the route we would prefer. Sometimes this may mean having to extend an existing codebase in order to keep within the technology required.</p>
<p>When embarking on a new project, we now make sure we establish the required sign-off devices as soon as possible. However, over the years have had our fingers burnt on more than one occasion, when we have run with a new way of doing something with good intentions, only for it to cause issues as we tried to get the site signed off. This just serves to remind us that there are so many device/user combos that it just isn’t OK if a given method will only work on certain browsers.</p>
<p>Although you can make workarounds and shims, there often isn’t budget to do this. And when a client doesn’t have the right resources then you need to go with the solution that will please everyone.</p>
<p>When it comes down to it, the main aim of the studio is to produce great, forward-thinking work, which means being fully open to new methods but also picking the right time and project to use them. It is a tricky balancing act, but one that gives me a great feeling of satisfaction, especially when a new process finally becomes ‘the standard’ on live projects.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/AJbi63b" target="_blank" rel="external">http://www.creativebloq.com/advice/beware-the-cutting-edge-of-web-design</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Progress in web design techniques shows no signs of slowing up. As the proponents of the early web are staggering around with thousand-ya
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Issue of lazy loading property</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/issue-of-lazy-loading-property/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/issue-of-lazy-loading-property/</id>
    <published>2017-06-30T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-30T10:03:41.547Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve got some<code>readonly</code>properties in my .h file. And when I tried to lazy loading them as usual like this.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">// MyView.h</div><div class="line">@property</div><div class="line"> (</div><div class="line">nonatomic</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">strong</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">readonly</div><div class="line">) </div><div class="line">UIImageView</div><div class="line"> *imageView;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">// MyView.m</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">- (</div><div class="line">UIImageView</div><div class="line"> *)imageView</div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">    </div><div class="line">if</div><div class="line"> (!_imageView)</div><div class="line">    &#123;</div><div class="line">        _imageView = [</div><div class="line">UIImageView</div><div class="line"> new];</div><div class="line">        _imageView.translatesAutoresizingMaskIntoConstraints = </div><div class="line">NO</div><div class="line">;</div><div class="line">        _imageView.backgroundColor = [</div><div class="line">UIColor</div><div class="line"> clearColor];</div><div class="line">        _imageView.contentMode = </div><div class="line">UIViewContentModeScaleAspectFit</div><div class="line">;</div><div class="line">        _imageView.userInteractionEnabled = </div><div class="line">NO</div><div class="line">;</div><div class="line">        _imageView.accessibilityIdentifier = </div><div class="line">@&quot;empty set image view&quot;</div><div class="line">;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">        _imageView.image = _defaultImage;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">        [_contentView addSubview:_imageView];</div><div class="line">    &#125;</div><div class="line">    </div><div class="line">return</div><div class="line"> _imageView;</div><div class="line">&#125;</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>Then…bang! It threw out errors in bulk, yelling “Use of undeclared identifier ‘_imageView’”. What the hell have I done!</p>
<p>Luckily, I found some explainations<a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/13670924/1594792" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>. It says:</p>
<p>Newer Xcode versions can create a @synthesize statement automatically and use the underscore prefix for instance variables. In this case however,since the property is read-only and you provide a getter method, Xcode does not synthesize the property automatically.</p>
<p>So, I have to @synthesize the property on my own, and now it’s quiet and cute again. :P</p>
<h4 id="—-Update-2017-05-30-—"><a href="#—-Update-2017-05-30-—" class="headerlink" title="— Update: 2017-05-30 —"></a>— Update: 2017-05-30 —</h4><p>I happened to recall this issue when clearing up the whole system of Objective-C. Let’s dig deeper about this issue and find if there’s a diamond in it. :P</p>
<p>This issue has references of two points:<code>@property</code>and<code>@synthesize</code>. Let’s dig more details one by one.</p>
<ul>
<li><code>@property</code><br>: I’d love to reference this paragraph of<br><a href="http://rypress.com/tutorials/objective-c/properties" target="_blank" rel="external">Ry’s Objective-C Tutorial</a><br>to show the goal of @property in Objective-C.</li>
</ul>
<p>An object’s properties let other objects inspect or change its state. But, in a well-designed object-oriented program, it’s not possible to directly access the internal state of an object. Instead, accessor methods (getters and setters) are used as an abstraction for interacting with the object’s underlying data.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/7raeeq3.png!web" alt=""></p>
<p>The goal of the @property directive is to make it easy to create and configure properties by automatically generating these accessor methods. It allows you to specify the behavior of a public property on a semantic level, and it takes care of the implementation details for you.</p>
<ul>
<li><code>@synthesize</code><br>: First of all, this feature is called<br><strong>autosynthesis</strong><br>of properties and it’s an<br><a href="http://clang.llvm.org/docs/LanguageExtensions.html#objective-c-autosynthesis-of-properties" target="_blank" rel="external">Objective-C language extension supported by clang</a><br>, which is the default compiler used by Xcode.</li>
</ul>
<p>Thanks to autosynthesis you don’t need to explicitly synthesize the property as it will be automatically synthesized by the compiler as<code>@synthesize propertyName = _propertyName</code>.</p>
<p>While, there’re some exceptions here:</p>
<ul>
<li>Readwrite property with custom getter and setter;</li>
<li>Readonly property with custom getter;</li>
<li>@dynamic (which is opposited to<br><code>@synthesize</code><br>);</li>
<li>Properites declared in a @protocol;</li>
<li>Properties declared in a category;</li>
<li>Overriden properties.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/QNryQrn.png!web" alt=""></p>
<p>In this condition, property<code>name</code>is set to be<code>readwrite</code>(as it is by default) with custom getter and setter. At this time, compiler believes that you want to take full control over<code>@property</code>manually, and then forbids autosynthesis for you.</p>
<p>We’ve already been used to not defining ivars on our own, once you have to use ivar, while autosynthesis is invalid, you’ll have to use<code>@synthesize</code>to compound ivars(i.e. let out the comment for line 24 in the image above).</p>
<p>Here’s a little sample.</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div><div class="line">19</div><div class="line">20</div><div class="line">21</div><div class="line">22</div><div class="line">23</div><div class="line">24</div><div class="line">25</div><div class="line">26</div><div class="line">27</div><div class="line">28</div><div class="line">29</div><div class="line">30</div><div class="line">31</div><div class="line">32</div><div class="line">33</div><div class="line">34</div><div class="line">35</div><div class="line">36</div><div class="line">37</div><div class="line">38</div><div class="line">39</div><div class="line">40</div><div class="line">41</div><div class="line">42</div><div class="line">43</div><div class="line">44</div><div class="line">45</div><div class="line">46</div><div class="line">47</div><div class="line">48</div><div class="line">49</div><div class="line">50</div><div class="line">51</div><div class="line">52</div><div class="line">53</div><div class="line">54</div><div class="line">55</div><div class="line">56</div><div class="line">57</div><div class="line">58</div><div class="line">59</div><div class="line">60</div><div class="line">61</div><div class="line">62</div><div class="line">63</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">@interface</div><div class="line">Car</div><div class="line">:</div><div class="line">NSObject</div><div class="line">@property</div><div class="line"> (</div><div class="line">strong</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">readwrite</div><div class="line">) </div><div class="line">NSString</div><div class="line"> *name;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">@end</div><div class="line">@implementation</div><div class="line">Car</div><div class="line">@end</div><div class="line">@interface</div><div class="line">Tesla</div><div class="line">:</div><div class="line">Car</div><div class="line">@property</div><div class="line"> (</div><div class="line">strong</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">readwrite</div><div class="line">) </div><div class="line">NSString</div><div class="line"> *name;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">@end</div><div class="line">@implementation</div><div class="line">Tesla</div><div class="line">@synthesize</div><div class="line"> name;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">- (</div><div class="line">void</div><div class="line">)printVar</div><div class="line">&#123;</div><div class="line">	</div><div class="line">super</div><div class="line">.name = </div><div class="line">@&quot;Car&quot;</div><div class="line">;</div><div class="line">	</div><div class="line">NSLog</div><div class="line">(</div><div class="line">@&quot;Tesla: Hello %@, ivar: %@，super: %@&quot;</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">self</div><div class="line">.name, </div><div class="line">self</div><div class="line">-</div><div class="line">&gt;</div><div class="line">name, </div><div class="line">super</div><div class="line">.name);</div><div class="line">&#125;</div><div class="line"></div><div class="line"></div><div class="line">@end</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>Output in console:</p>
<figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><div class="line">1</div><div class="line">2</div><div class="line">3</div><div class="line">4</div><div class="line">5</div><div class="line">6</div><div class="line">7</div><div class="line">8</div><div class="line">9</div><div class="line">10</div><div class="line">11</div><div class="line">12</div><div class="line">13</div><div class="line">14</div><div class="line">15</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">17</div><div class="line">18</div></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><div class="line">2017-06-30</div><div class="line">16</div><div class="line">:02</div><div class="line">:03.946</div><div class="line">BlockSample</div><div class="line">[86278:38771956]</div><div class="line">Tesla</div><div class="line">: </div><div class="line">Hello</div><div class="line">Tesla</div><div class="line">, </div><div class="line">ivar</div><div class="line">: </div><div class="line">Tesla</div><div class="line">，</div><div class="line">super</div><div class="line">: </div><div class="line">Car</div></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>It’s also fine to get subclass’s ivar<code>name</code>simply by<code>name</code>.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/mQJbiaj" target="_blank" rel="external">http://www.calios.gq/2017/05/30/Issue-of-lazy-loading-property/</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;I’ve got some&lt;code&gt;readonly&lt;/code&gt;properties in my .h file. And when I tried to lazy loading them as usual like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Get epic graphic design skills and the diploma to prove it</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/get-epic-graphic-design-skills-and-the-diploma-to-prove-it/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/get-epic-graphic-design-skills-and-the-diploma-to-prove-it/</id>
    <published>2017-06-30T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-30T10:03:41.544Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/BvQbAzQ.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>You know when you see a simple new company logo then hear that they paid<strong>half a million dollars</strong>for it? A graphic designer did that. If you want to get in on this action, the<a href="https://goo.gl/LEaxcr" target="_blank" rel="external"><strong>Graphic Design Certification School</strong></a>can teach you the skills <strong>and get you certified</strong>in the process.</p>
<p>It’s not enough to be creative these days, to make it as a designer you need to have an<strong>intimate knowledge of the software</strong>. This learning kit comprises<strong>expert training</strong>in the big three Adobe design packages.</p>
<h2 id="Here’s-what-you-get"><a href="#Here’s-what-you-get" class="headerlink" title="Here’s what you get:"></a>Here’s what you get:</h2><p><a href="https://goo.gl/LEaxcr" target="_blank" rel="external">Photoshop Course</a>– $399 value</p>
<p><a href="https://goo.gl/LEaxcr" target="_blank" rel="external">InDesign Course</a>– $399 value</p>
<p><a href="https://goo.gl/LEaxcr" target="_blank" rel="external">Illustrator Course</a>– $399 value</p>
<p>Starting from the basics you’ll<strong>learn everything you need to know</strong>about<strong>creating and editing images and documents</strong>for print or online publishing. From fundamentals like pixels to layering and creating 3D images. You’ll<strong>also learn the need-to-know details</strong>associated with graphic design, such as image rights.</p>
<p>You could sign up for these courses out of<strong>pure interest</strong>, but there are<strong>great extras</strong>too. The package is<strong>CPD certified</strong>so you’re both learning and accumulating CPD hours. If that doesn’t mean much to you, then how about this – Each course includes an online assessment, which leads to<strong>a DTP Master Diploma</strong>. How do you like those apples.</p>
<p>You’ll learn everything you need to know about creating and editing images</p>
<p>There’s a stonking<a href="https://goo.gl/LEaxcr" target="_blank" rel="external"><strong>96% discount</strong></a>on this toolkit right now, so this tasty bundle is all yours for<a href="https://goo.gl/LEaxcr" target="_blank" rel="external"><strong>just $39.</strong></a>That’s for<strong>lifetime access</strong>too, so if you fancy taking it on at any time then<strong> sign up now while it’s on offer.</strong></p>
<p>Don’t leave it too late.<strong>Hit the button below</strong>to join the 2,000 people already enrolled.</p>
<p><a href="https://goo.gl/LEaxcr" target="_blank" rel="external">check it out!</a></p>
<p>Is this deal not quite right for you? Head over to the<a href="https://goo.gl/WPGPbB" target="_blank" rel="external">AAPICKS HUB</a>for more savings you’re going to love! For notifications of offers and price drops, sign up for our<a href="https://goo.gl/WbwVpc" target="_blank" rel="external">Deal Alerts</a>newsletter.</p>
<p>We may get a small percent from purchases made through our posts. However, the AA Picks team only showcases verified, legitimate deals. It’s a nice way to help keep the lights on around here, and it decreases our reliance on pesky ads. If you have questions or concerns, please reach out at<a href="mailto:aapicks@androidauthority.com" target="_blank" rel="external">aapicks@androidauthority.com</a>.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/j6nEnm" target="_blank" rel="external">http://www.androidauthority.com/graphic-design-school-2-782862/</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img1.tuicool.com/BvQbAzQ.jpg!web&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know when you see a simple new company logo then hear that they pai
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bid Farewell to These 6 Worst Website Design Habits</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/bid-farewell-to-these-6-worst-website-design-habits/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/bid-farewell-to-these-6-worst-website-design-habits/</id>
    <published>2017-06-30T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-30T10:03:41.540Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Your website is the primary online identity of your business. Hence, it has to be flawless. It is the space through which your potential clients can gather all their information on your company. A well designed<a href="https://www.perth-web-design.com.au/website-design-portfolio/" target="_blank" rel="external">web design</a>can make or break your business. Hence, it is crucial that you avoid some of the common design mistakes which do not speak well to the visitors.</p>
<h2 id="Lack-of-User-Friendliness"><a href="#Lack-of-User-Friendliness" class="headerlink" title="Lack of User Friendliness"></a>Lack of User Friendliness</h2><p>The first and foremost thing to keep in mind while designing your website is its user friendliness. You cannot assume all of your visitors to be extremely tech savvy. If your website is not easy to access and browse through for users of different levels of technological competence, it can give rise to frustration, which in turn, will make them customers abandon your space. Therefore, make sure all the necessary content or contact information is displayed clearly. Use easily accessible menu tabs, call to action buttons and whatever else it takes to ensure a smooth experience for your visitors.</p>
<h2 id="Thoughtless-use-of-Colors"><a href="#Thoughtless-use-of-Colors" class="headerlink" title="Thoughtless use of Colors"></a>Thoughtless use of Colors</h2><p>It is important to know what your company represents and how to present all of it though your web design. Using the right kind of color scheme and design is crucial else you might end up<a href="https://tech.co/employee-benefits-package-millennial-2017-01" target="_blank" rel="external">damaging your company’s image</a>. Choose your colors wisely, keeping in mind the image you want to portray. Keep it simple but stunning. First, decide if you want a complimentary or contrasting color scheme, and once decided, stick to it.</p>
<h2 id="Lack-of-White-Space"><a href="#Lack-of-White-Space" class="headerlink" title="Lack of White Space"></a>Lack of White Space</h2><p>If there is one thing that annoys a visitor infinitely, it is the lack of white space. White space is a stretch of blank space on your website, which is intended to strike a balance between the matter so as to ensure a better view of the content. Gone are the shiny, glittery designs of the nineties where websites tend to cram everything into one page. Minimalism offers a clean look which helps your viewer focus on the content better.</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/7FRVNbQ.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="Autoplays-and-Pop-Ups"><a href="#Autoplays-and-Pop-Ups" class="headerlink" title="Autoplays and Pop Ups"></a>Autoplays and Pop Ups</h2><p>Often websites choose to include a small pop up page to ask their users to register or to advertise their content but it is not an advisable design. Concentrate more on the content than on such mindless advertisement. If your website is informative and well structured, viewers will automatically choose to register or look into your other content. Don’t distract your visitors with an annoying pop up. Similarly, autoplay can be an extremely infuriating feature on a website. For example, if someone is checking your website out at work or on a cab, it can be frustrating if an<a href="http://www.dreamytricks.net/free-music-download-apps-for-android/" target="_blank" rel="external">music starts playing automatically</a>. Give your users the choice to play it instead of forcing it upon them.</p>
<h2 id="Slow-Loading-Design"><a href="#Slow-Loading-Design" class="headerlink" title="Slow Loading Design"></a>Slow Loading Design</h2><p>Always keep this in mind that your viewers will not spend an extra second waiting for your website to load. Therefore, make sure that your website is not too loaded to compromise loading speed. You can get rid of heavy designs like carousels, too many pictures, videos, etc., which slow down the loading process. Make sure you put only the most essential content on your page above the fold. Your user will not mind scrolling over to the next page but aslow loading page will definitely make you lose out on visitors.</p>
<h2 id="Non-Responsive-Design"><a href="#Non-Responsive-Design" class="headerlink" title="Non Responsive Design"></a>Non Responsive Design</h2><p>As more and more people are shifting to hand held mobile devices to access the internet, it is almost a crime to not make your website mobile responsive. Lack of responsiveness will not only make your website difficult to view on a smaller device like a tablet or a mobile phone, it will also push down your ratings on the Google search, which can be disastrous for any website.</p>
<p>Design your website wisely as it is the face of your company. It is what gives your potential clients an idea about your organization and helps you turn your visitors into clients. Hence, avoid these mistakes to ensure an excellent viewing experience for your visitors.</p>
<p>Read more<a href="https://tech.co/entrepreneur/development-design" target="_blank" rel="external">about designing a quality website for your company</a>at TechCo</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/ENfiyi3" target="_blank" rel="external">https://tech.co/bid-farewell-worst-design-habits-2017-06</a> </p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Your website is the primary online identity of your business. Hence, it has to be flawless. It is the space through which your potential 
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The 5-Minute Interview: Anirban Chatterjee &amp; Keshav Ranganathan, IBM</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/the-5-minute-interview-anirban-chatterjee-and-keshav-ranganathan-ibm/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/the-5-minute-interview-anirban-chatterjee-and-keshav-ranganathan-ibm/</id>
    <published>2017-06-30T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-30T10:03:41.555Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>ByRachel Howard, Community Editor | June 30, 2017</p>
<p>“As the relationship really started to take shape, we realized what the two technologies could solve much more effectively when they worked together,”said<a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/keshavranganathan" target="_blank" rel="external">Keshav Ranganathan</a>, Senior Offering Manager at<a href="http://www-03.ibm.com/systems/power/solutions/bigdata-analytics/" target="_blank" rel="external">IBM Power Systems</a>.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/ArQ36jj.jpg!web" alt="">The Neo4j partnership with IBM Power Systems is one of many that have been formed over the last several years, making the native graph database an even more effective enterprise solution for companies that span industries and continents.</p>
<p>In this week’s 5-Minute Interview (conducted at<a href="http://graphconnect.com/?ref=blog" target="_blank" rel="external">GraphConnect San Francisco</a>), we discuss the ways in which the IBM Power Systems and Neo4j partnership came to fruition, and the powerful benefits both companies are able to provide to customers because of it.</p>
<h3 id="Talk-to-us-about-why-you-all-at-IBM-Power-Systems-decided-to-partner-with-Neo4j"><a href="#Talk-to-us-about-why-you-all-at-IBM-Power-Systems-decided-to-partner-with-Neo4j" class="headerlink" title="Talk to us about why you all at IBM Power Systems decided to partner with Neo4j."></a>Talk to us about why you all at IBM Power Systems decided to partner with Neo4j.</h3><p>Anirban Chatterjee:We partnered with Neo4j because of the hover platform that we sell,<a href="http://www-03.ibm.com/systems/power/" target="_blank" rel="external">IBM Power Systems</a>.</p>
<p>We’ve been working withNeo4j to optimize it to run even more efficiently onIBM POWER8. In fact, we’re at about 80-90% faster per price performance on Power Systems compared to the equivalent x86. Which means that if you were to buy two socket servers from us instead of Intel, we’ll provide up to 80 or 90% better performance.</p>
<p>At a base level, that’s the value we offer. On top of that, we’ve been doing some work with Neo4j to add<a href="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/community/blogs/fe313521-2e95-46f2-817d-44a4f27eba32/entry/power8_capi_flash_in_memory_expansion_to_speed_data_access?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="external">CAPI Flash support</a>. This means you can search large graphs in memory without high memory costs, because of the ability to take flash memory and hook it directly into the system.</p>
<p>This makes it act more like real memory without all the latencies you see with flash, so it’s a much cheaper way to get a large graph onto the system.</p>
<h3 id="What-made-you-choose-to-work-with-Neo4j"><a href="#What-made-you-choose-to-work-with-Neo4j" class="headerlink" title="What made you choose to work with Neo4j?"></a>What made you choose to work with Neo4j?</h3><p>Keshav Ranganathan:We first looked at the capabilities of graphs, such as searching large amounts of data and uncoveringnew relationships. And when you look at some of the IBM Power System capabilities and the amount of memory that can be on a single system, we knew we had to support both scale-out and scale-up configurations.</p>
<p>It seemed like a natural partnership, especially as databases were becoming much larger and with the emergence of big data. As the partnership really started to take shape, we realized what the two technologies could solve much more effectively when they worked together.</p>
<p>What is the most interesting result or project you’ve encountered through your partnership with Neo4j?</p>
<p>Ranganathan:We are getting clients jointly, in which we see huge opportunities. This is especially true as data size grows beyond a terabyte of data, or maybe a few hundred million nodes. What we jointly bring to the table is going to make a huge different for our clients, and we’re really looking forward to this partnership.</p>
<h3 id="Can-you-tell-us-more-about-IBM’s-partnership-with-Neo4j"><a href="#Can-you-tell-us-more-about-IBM’s-partnership-with-Neo4j" class="headerlink" title="Can you tell us more about IBM’s partnership with Neo4j?"></a>Can you tell us more about IBM’s partnership with Neo4j?</h3><p>Ranganathan:Well, this is not really a client partnership; rather it’s a synergistic partnership between two vendors, who bring technologies jointly to market to address client needs. I think we are making really good progress, and I’m happy with where we are in terms of our relationship with Neo4j.</p>
<p>The new Causal Clustering capabilities are quite exciting, and we’re going to make sure we have that capability on Power Systems. We’re also leveraging some of the capabilities in Power Systems to increase scalability, and we are really looking forward to growing our partnership.</p>
<h3 id="Is-there-anything-else-you’d-like-to-add-or-say"><a href="#Is-there-anything-else-you’d-like-to-add-or-say" class="headerlink" title="Is there anything else you’d like to add or say?"></a>Is there anything else you’d like to add or say?</h3><p>Ranganathan:It’s pretty exciting to hear how much the community has grown over the last several years; that<a href="http://graphconnect.com/?ref=blog" target="_blank" rel="external">GraphConnect</a>was a 200 person event in 2012 and is now a 1300 person event — that’s phenomenal.</p>
<p>And it’s really interesting to learn about the connected enterprise concept in terms of data, relationship between data, and how to extract insight from the data. Watching Neo4j transform from a niche tool applied in a handful of cases to being an enterprise solution is really exciting as well. We look forward to the continued growth ofgraph databases, Neo4j and IBM Power Systems.</p>
<p><em>Want to share about your Neo4j project in a future 5-Minute Interview? Drop us a line atcontent@neo4j.com</em></p>
<p>Learn more about running Neo4j on IBM POWER8 with CAPI Flash: Click below to get all the information you need on large scale graph processing with IBM Power Systems and Neo4j.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/mMfEVnU" target="_blank" rel="external">https://neo4j.com/blog/anirban-chatterjee-keshav-ranganathan-ibm/</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;ByRachel Howard, Community Editor | June 30, 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As the relationship really started to take shape, we realized what the two tech
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Minoca OS 0.4: We love the eighties!</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/minoca-os-04-we-love-the-eighties/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/30/minoca-os-04-we-love-the-eighties/</id>
    <published>2017-06-30T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-30T10:06:34.697Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/AzmmqmR.png!web" alt=""></p>
<p>fceux running on the first Minoca OS X server</p>
<p>We’re pleased to announce the release of version 0.4 of Minoca OS. In the eight months since we released 0.3, our very first open source release, a lot has changed. Most notably Minoca is now sporting the_early_signs of a desktop. And of course no desktop would be complete without an application to run on it. So we’ve added<a href="http://www.fceux.com/web/home.html" target="_blank" rel="external">fceux</a>, an NES emulator, which we used to test both graphics performance and sound. Hopefully you’ll be better at Super Mario Brothers than Chris, who I watched blatantly kill Mario probably upwards of 50 times in the name of testing sound. Here’s what, how, and why we did it.</p>
<p>For those who have never heard of us before, Minoca OS is a new operating system built completely from the ground up. It’s designed to be lean, portable, modular, and modern (NES emulator notwithstanding). We’re trying to do more with less, so devices with limited power and resource budgets can get full OS functionality with minimal overhead.</p>
<h3 id="What’s-New"><a href="#What’s-New" class="headerlink" title="What’s New"></a>What’s New</h3><p>Some new drivers in 0.4:</p>
<ul>
<li>AHCI (the controller usually behind your SATA port)</li>
<li>e1000 (Intel gigabit networking driver)</li>
<li>USB and PS/2 mouse</li>
<li>Intel HD Audio and Raspberry Pi PWM audio</li>
</ul>
<p>Some new third-party packages worth noting:</p>
<ul>
<li>Xorg-server</li>
<li>SDL</li>
<li>fceux (NES emulator)</li>
<li>miniDLNA</li>
<li>Mesa3D (software rendering)</li>
<li>GTK+</li>
</ul>
<p>You can grab the latest OS images on ourdownloads page. Bugs and feature requests can be filed on our<a href="https://github.com/minoca/os" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub</a>page. You can fire up X for yourself by running “opkg update; opkg install fceux xinit; startx”.</p>
<h3 id="Motivation"><a href="#Motivation" class="headerlink" title="Motivation"></a>Motivation</h3><p>First of all I’d like to say a huge thank you to everyone who tried out Minoca OS since we went open source back in November. An even bigger thank you goes to the intrepid folks who submitted bugs and pull requests on our GitHub page. Chris and I really appreciate that, please continue to do it!</p>
<p>One of the requests we seemed to get a lot was “where’s the GUI” or “can I run this graphical application XYZ?” When we launched 0.3 we had done no work towards a graphical environment, mostly citing the fact that accelerated graphics are hard. That’s still true, and we still don’t have accelerated graphics (remember these are the_beginnings_of a desktop), but we were curious to find out how far out we were from having some sort of basic graphical environment.</p>
<p>The goal here was not to put out 0.4 with the message of “behold, the glorious desktop GUI has arrived”, but rather to provide the elements and building blocks for people familiar with compiling software to potentially make progress on their own.</p>
<h3 id="All-Roads-Lead-to-X"><a href="#All-Roads-Lead-to-X" class="headerlink" title="All Roads Lead to X"></a>All Roads Lead to X</h3><p>Our initial thought was actually to port over DirectFB, a Linux library for interacting directly with the frame buffer. In fact we went so far as to port DirectFB to Minoca. Things fell apart a bit when we went looking for applications built on top of DirectFB. There aren’t so many of those. Wayland/Weston looks super cool and new, but it also appeared to be pretty Linux-specific, so it didn’t seem like the ideal choice to start with. No, everything graphical seems to compile against X. The ancient terrifying medusa that is X. It was on the very bottom of my mental list of possible options, but it was becoming clear that it really was the_only_option.</p>
<p>X is not just one thing that you download and compile. It’s composed of over a hundred different packages. As developers of a new OS, we generally feel it’s a pretty good day if we’ve added one or two new packages. The idea of adding over 100 new packages even if they all ported perfectly seems daunting. And though we’ve worked hard to build a POSIX compatible C library, life has a way of not going that smoothly.</p>
<h3 id="Into-the-Abyss"><a href="#Into-the-Abyss" class="headerlink" title="Into the Abyss"></a>Into the Abyss</h3><p>There’s really no way to check and see if you’re going to get stuck on a missing OS feature in package number 67 of 140, you just have to start building and hope the obstacles are surmountable. The chapter on X in the<a href="http://www.linuxfromscratch.org/blfs/view/svn/x/installing.html" target="_blank" rel="external">Linux From Scratch</a>book is a precious map in an otherwise endless labyrinth. I have no idea how anyone built the X server before that book. Most of it isn’t super Linux-specific, with some light editing they could call it “Any OS From Scratch”.</p>
<p>It also helps that nearly everything is autoconfed. Not that I don’t struggle with autoconf and especially libtool, but I’d say autoconf and I have an “understanding” with each other. It’s the devil I know, at least.</p>
<p>The first batch of 25 or so packages contain mostly headers. A warmup round to get your fingers loose, I suppose. Then comes another batch of 30 or so library packages. To my surprise these seem to go by pretty smoothly, and even cross compile!</p>
<p>I hit my biggest obstacle with Mesa, the 3D graphics library responsible for libraries like libGL. Mesa was one of the few non-Xorg packages in the quest for the X server, and required some monkeying to get right. Supplying the right configure parameters for a non-Linux software-only pipeline that the X server was happy with took some trial and error. There were also a few OS-specific bits of code that needed the obligatory “and here’s Minoca, too” code snippets. The nastiest<a href="https://bugs.freedesktop.org/show_bug.cgi?id=35268" target="_blank" rel="external">barb</a>, which I’d only discover later, was their forced use of the “initial-exec” thread-local storage model. I know this was done in the name of performance, but it leaves a bit of a mess for the OS designers, who either have to 1) accommodate it with a brittle “might work for Mesa but I hope no one else does this” kind of hack, or 2) force programs using libGL to load it on initial program load, which the X server wouldn’t have ordinarily done. We went for option 2, which leaves you feeling only slightly less dirty.</p>
<p>The remaining packages leading up to running an X server went surprisingly smoothly. My compliments to the Xorg developers. Xterm, a non-Xorg package, required a bit of work. There are some code bases that have a “shove your OS in here with ifdefs” vibe to them, xterm is one of those. It’s usually pretty easy to do, but it never feels very good.</p>
<h3 id="Minoca-I-O"><a href="#Minoca-I-O" class="headerlink" title="Minoca I/O"></a>Minoca I/O</h3><p>In theory we had a running X server, but given that X couldn’t display video or receive input, there wasn’t much proof. I added Minoca framebuffer support, and wrote an input driver to allow X to gather keyboard and mouse events from the kernel. This also required actually adding mouse support to Minoca, including a USB HID parser. After some false starts, I was presented with this beauty:</p>
<p>Source:　<a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/yyYNjyB" target="_blank" rel="external">https://blog.minocacorp.com/minoca-os-0-4-we-love-the-eighties-170a93112db1</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img0.tuicool.com/AzmmqmR.png!web&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fceux running on the first Minoca OS X server&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re pleased to a
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>pnpm version 1 is out!</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/pnpm-version-1-is-out/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/pnpm-version-1-is-out/</id>
    <published>2017-06-28T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-28T10:01:53.439Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="pnpm-version-1-is-out"><a href="#pnpm-version-1-is-out" class="headerlink" title="_pnpm_version 1 is out!"></a>_pnpm_version 1 is out!</h2><p>Today we’re excited to announce the release of<a href="https://github.com/pnpm/pnpm" target="_blank" rel="external">pnpm</a>1!</p>
<p>Why only now? The initial commit to pnpm was made byRico Sta. Cruz on<a href="https://github.com/pnpm/pnpm/commit/4b42e5fcc402310d028ac54ba8fe979f7c4470af" target="_blank" rel="external">Jan 27, 2016</a>. It was based on the ideas of<a href="https://github.com/alexanderGugel/ied" target="_blank" rel="external">ied</a>by<a href="https://twitter.com/alexanderGugel" target="_blank" rel="external">Alexander Gugel</a>with initial commit on<a href="https://github.com/alexanderGugel/ied/commit/d8bae2d63750030b019e9653ce9ea71de93be5c7" target="_blank" rel="external">Aug 6, 2015</a>!</p>
<p>Unlike<em>Yarn</em>, which has decided to use the same<strong>node_modules</strong>structure that_npm_creates,_pnpm_uses a completely new approach (about which you can read more inthis article). It was_really_hard to make a symlinked<strong>node_modules</strong>structure work with most of the existing npm packages! All the different problems that we have encountered and the dozens of breaking changes we had to make, deserves a post of its own. Finally, almost 2 years since the idea of a symlinked<strong>node_modules</strong>structure has born, we can tell with confidence: it is possible and<strong>it does work</strong>.</p>
<h3 id="So-what-does-version-1-mean"><a href="#So-what-does-version-1-mean" class="headerlink" title="So what does version 1 mean?"></a>So what does version 1 mean?</h3><p>Version 1 means that:</p>
<ul>
<li>The<br><a href="https://github.com/pnpm/pnpm/blob/master/docs/about-the-package-store.md" target="_blank" rel="external">store structure</a><br>that pnpm uses since<br><a href="https://github.com/pnpm/pnpm/releases/tag/v0.70.0" target="_blank" rel="external">version 0.70</a><br>is reliable enough and we are confident that there will be no need in breaking changes in its structure.</li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/pnpm/pnpm/blob/master/docs/symlinked-node-modules-structure.md" target="_blank" rel="external">The<strong>node_modules</strong>layout</a><br>that pnpm creates works with most of the ecosystem.</p>
<p><em>pnpm@1</em><br>also ships with an experimental<br><strong>node_modules</strong><br>layout that can be turned on with the<br><a href="https://github.com/pnpm/pnpm#independent-leaves" target="_blank" rel="external">independent-leaves</a><br>config. The experimental layout boosts installation speed by 8% and works almost with all projects. However, we were not confident enough to make it the default yet.</p>
</li>
<li>The format of the<br><strong>shrinkwrap.yaml</strong><br>file, which is pnpm’s lockfile, is good enough for being committed to VCS.</li>
<li>When possible,<br><em>pnpm@1</em><br>works the way<br><em>npm@5</em><br>does.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can rely on these things and they won’t get breaking changes in version 1.</p>
<h3 id="What’s-next"><a href="#What’s-next" class="headerlink" title="What’s next?"></a>What’s next?</h3><p>Even faster!The goal is to make installations<em>subsecond fast</em>. So fast that it would run on every Git operation. Maybe one day it would be even integrated to Git?!</p>
<p>As of now, pnpm is faster than Yarn when installing with cold cache but may be a bit slower in different scenarios. For a detailed comparison of npm/pnpm/Yarn speed, see “<a href="https://intoli.com/blog/node-package-manager-benchmarks/" target="_blank" rel="external">Why I still don’t use Yarn</a>”. However, there is no reason for pnpm to be slower than Yarn or npm. So we’ll have to find the issues and make pnpm faster.</p>
<p>Simpler codebase.pnpm is currently very hard to contribute to, so it will have to be split into separate packages. The first step will probably be separation of the installation engine.</p>
<p>PR.Although pnpm is public for a longer period of time than Yarn, it is far less popular. So more articles, more documentation, and more interesting tools will be created to promote pnpm. Let’s make our<a href="https://github.com/pnpm/awesome-pnpm" target="_blank" rel="external">awesome list</a>huge!</p>
<h3 id="Try-it"><a href="#Try-it" class="headerlink" title="Try it"></a>Try it</h3><p>Just install pnpm via npm:<code>npm install -g pnpm</code>. And use it instead of npm whenever you want to install something:<code>pnpm i foo</code>.</p>
<p>Also, you can read more info at the<a href="https://github.com/pnpm/pnpm" target="_blank" rel="external">pnpm GitHub repo</a>. You can follow<a href="https://twitter.com/pnpmjs" target="_blank" rel="external">pnpm on Twitter</a>or ask for help at the<a href="https://gitter.im/pnpm/pnpm" target="_blank" rel="external">pnpm Gitter Chat Room</a>.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/euQnUn7" target="_blank" rel="external">https://medium.com/pnpm/pnpm-version-1-is-out-935a07af914</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;pnpm-version-1-is-out&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pnpm-version-1-is-out&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;_pnpm_version 1 is out!&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;_pnpm_version 1 is ou
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Google News shows off its minimalist new look</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/google-news-shows-off-its-minimalist-new-look/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/google-news-shows-off-its-minimalist-new-look/</id>
    <published>2017-06-28T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-28T10:01:53.436Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google today rolled out a brand new look for News. The redesign is modern, clutter-free, and puts the emphasis on what’s important when browsing dozens of news stories.</p>
<p>According to Google:</p>
<p>“To make news more accessible and easier to navigate, we redesigned the desktop website with a renewed focus on facts, diverse perspectives, and more control for users.”</p>
<p>Scrolling through the news feed, you’ll find easily scannable content.Google’s Story card format allowsusers to quickly pinpoint key bits of information like news source, headline, and publish time. The Story cards also allow users to look at the different perspectives surrounding the story ー encouraging readers to gain a more informative understanding of the issue.</p>
<p>And if you glance at the top of the page, you’ll see a new navigation bar for “Headlines,” “Local” and “For You.” “Local” is exactly what it sounds like ー keeping tabs on stories from any part of the world. And then there’s “For You,” a feature that personalizes the news feed based on your interests.</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/73uyMnN.png!web" alt=""></p>
<p>The icing on the cake is the Fact Check block, which makes it a lot easier to vet a story’s credibility.</p>
<p>The feature is only available to US readers at the moment, but Google plans to slowly roll out the update globally.</p>
<p><a href="https://thenextweb.com/company/google/" target="_blank" rel="external">Google</a><a href="https://thenextweb.com/section/insights/" target="_blank" rel="external">Insights</a></p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/3yquAfB" target="_blank" rel="external">https://thenextweb.com/google/2017/06/28/google-news-shows-off-its-minimalist-new-look/</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Google today rolled out a brand new look for News. The redesign is modern, clutter-free, and puts the emphasis on what’s important when b
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Repetition, Pattern, and Rhythm</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/repetition-pattern-and-rhythm/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/repetition-pattern-and-rhythm/</id>
    <published>2017-06-28T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-28T10:01:53.444Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let’s look at three subjects that, at first glance, may strike you as being incredibly basic and self-explanatory. However, although they mayseemlike they should need no introduction, we should study them. By understanding these concepts, you’ll be able to apply them more effectively to captivate your users’ attention while making your designs more effective.</p>
<p>Say “repetition” and you might think about someone who says the same thing over and over again. However, it’s different indesign. Repeating things does not have to be boring! In fact, it canempowera design when used in the right way. It can also ensure that messages are better understood. As designers, we have threerepetition methods:<strong>repetition</strong>,<strong>patterns</strong>, and<strong>rhythm</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="Repetition"><a href="#Repetition" class="headerlink" title="Repetition"></a>Repetition</h2><p>Repetition is simply repeating a single element many times in a design. For example, you could draw aline horizontally and then draw several others next to it.</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/qyeMfyB.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Repetition can be useful in web and app design. For example, you’d expect the logo of a business to be repeated on every page and in the same place. Menu items are also often repeated in the same place on a page. This helps provide a consistentuser experience. By repeatingelements, we as designers not onlydeliver according to our users’expectations in this way, but we also improve their experience. Our being consistent makes the users more comfortable. Remember that the eye works in a certain way by default. Using repetition to keep the eye familiar with our design’s elements means we’re taking advantage of this tendency. We can also use shapes, colors, textures, fonts, etc. to maintain this consistency via repetition.</p>
<p>You can also achieve repetition by using repeated messages. If you want your customers to know that you’re the cheapest or the fastest in the business, you’ll want to tell them that on more than one occasion if you want the message to stick. In this instance, we use repetition forreinforcement. You may rememberlearning your times tables by repeating them until you drummed them into your mind. The principle here is the same. We retain information better the more often we encounter it and internalize it.</p>
<h2 id="Pattern"><a href="#Pattern" class="headerlink" title="Pattern"></a>Pattern</h2><p>Patterns are simply a repetition of more tan one design element working in concert with each other. Aseamless patternis one where every element within a design (no matter how often it’s repeated) combines to form a whole. This is most common in backgrounds on web and app pages. It’s also popular in carpet and wallpaper design. Look around you: your bed cover, wall, notebook cover. If you see a seamless pattern, look at it closely. Do you see how the elements (circles, spirals, cones, pineapples, etc.) appear again and again in the same way? Sometimes, they touch; sometimes, they have space between them.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/qYzEJfu.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Author/Copyright holder: Dirk Stoop. Copyright terms and licence: CC BY-NC 2.0</p>
<p>As you might expect, designers base most patterns on colors, textures and shapes, rather than words. We can recognize shapes far more quickly than words, which we have to read, no matter how quickly. You can find such patterns in architecture, too. Architects tend to include a unifying motif on the inside and outside of buildings to enhance the aesthetic appeal. This is nothing new. Think of ancient Greek buildings such as the Parthenon. Ancient designers could be ingenious in their use of patterns of such elements as lines and spirals.</p>
<p>When you consider using patterns in your web or app design, you’ll want to think about the pattern’s complexity. While it might seem like a nice idea to tile a single image as a background, this can make it much harder to read the text that lies over the pattern. If you want tocreate a design for a site that deals with travel to Greece, you could use the top of an ancient column for your design. At first, it looks great; you’ve got a beautiful design that features circles and grape leaves.</p>
<p>However, you still have to add text. So, writing over this, you soon notice a problem. The dark writing sometimes falls over the image’s dark lines. You could use brighter text, such as white or yellow, but you’ll find that the gray stone makes it hard to read, too.You’rehaving trouble reading it, and so will your users. They want to engage with your design, not work to try and read text.Simplicity andsubtlety are key considerations if you want to maintain the user experience, keeping usersonyour page.</p>
<h2 id="Rhythm"><a href="#Rhythm" class="headerlink" title="Rhythm"></a>Rhythm</h2><p>When you repeat elements, the intervals between those repetitions can create a sense of rhythm in the viewer and a sense ofmovement. Musicians create rhythm in the spacing between notes, effectively making these “silent” gapsplay offthe notes. Designers insert spacing between elements to makerhythm. There are, broadly speaking, five types of visual rhythm.</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/AfeAVnA.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Author/Copyright holder: Eden-Lys. Copyright terms and licence: CC BY-NC-ND 2.0</p>
<p><strong>Random rhythm</strong>–Repeating elements with nospecific regular interval creates random rhythms. The spacing could be a millimeter here, a centimeter there, while the elements could be all over the place. Think of falling snow, pebbles on a beach, traffic movements: they are all examples of random rhythms in action.</p>
<p>It’s also worth noting that a rhythm mayappearrandom if you examine asmall section of the rhythm. However, if you step back and examine a larger section, it may be that there is a regular but complex rhythm applied to the design. Remember that you have positive and negative images, which you can use so that both the elements and the spaces between them make your design hard to “predict”. By using a larger series of elements, you’ll have virtually limitless possibilities toplay with. The artist René Magritte made particularly interesting use of random rhythm.</p>
<p><strong>Regular rhythm</strong>–Like the beating of aheart, the regular rhythm follows the same intervals over and over again. You can easily make a regular rhythm just by creating a grid or a series of vertical lines. The user’s eye will instantly recognize a regular rhythm, scanning it for any irregularities in the process. Remember, the eye “likes” to be drawn to outstanding elements. Therefore, there is a risk that when you’re using a regular rhythm in a design that it can become monotonous (like the dripping of a tap).</p>
<p><strong>Alternating rhythm</strong>–You can repeat more than one element in a design. In an alternating design, you use a 1-2-1-2-1-2 pattern. Think of the black and white squares on a chessboard: that’s an alternating rhythm in play. An alternating rhythm is, in fact, a regular rhythm with more complexity. It could be as straightforward as our chessboard, or we could envision something more intricate. Some fantastic alternating rhythms include rows of fish, birds, or other animals. Taking fish as an example, we can see that each identical fish is following another. Below, the sequence is repeated; however, thenegative space betweenthe rows shows fish of theothercolor (which we take to be the background) swimming the other way, the fine lines of their fins and tails interlocking with those of the first pattern of fish. M.C. Escher’sLizard(1942) is another great example of this, incorporating three colors of lizards with a pair of lizards of each color facing away from each other, tail to tail. As simple or complex as we want to make an alternating rhythm, it can be an easy way to break up the monotony of a regular rhythm.</p>
<p><strong>Flowing rhythm</strong>–A flowing rhythm shows the repeated elements following bends, curves, and undulations. In nature, you can see this in the waves on a beach or sand dunes. As designers, we can mimic nature by making wonderful patterns of elements with flowing rhythm. We can show clumps of seaweed underwater, their strands gently facing in a series of directions. The user imagines them washing against each other.</p>
<p><strong>Progressive rhythm</strong>–We can make a progressive rhythm simply by changing one characteristic of a motif as we repeat it. We could draw a series of circles, one above the other, making each lower one larger. Do you see how the largest one at the bottom looks like it’s closest to you? We can make a progressive rhythm change subtly or dramatically. You could add shade to the smaller circles progressively so that the smallest one at the top is dark, the middle one in partial shade, and the biggest one only slightly shaded. Progressive rhythms surround us. If you were tovideo someone dancing and then examine that video frame-by-frame, you would have a progressive rhythm.</p>
<h2 id="Designing-with-Repetition-Pattern-and-Rhythm"><a href="#Designing-with-Repetition-Pattern-and-Rhythm" class="headerlink" title="Designing with Repetition, Pattern, and Rhythm"></a>Designing with Repetition, Pattern, and Rhythm</h2><p>The use of repeated visual elements is a technique designers commonly employ inweb design. You can repeat design elements, for example, to provide a consistent visual experience. It will make it easier for users to focus on the content because they know where they can find specific types of content ornavigation options.</p>
<p>You can also use repetition to draw attention to a particular area of content or design. You can use it to show relationships between content blocks, too.</p>
<p>Also, you can use patterns for backgrounds to addtexture and consistency, and you can deploy them to deliver consistency between pages of the same type.</p>
<p>As designers, we can use rhythm to create excitement (building gradually over time) or reassurance (a heartbeat might be perfect on a page aimed at expectant mothers, for example). Or, we can use it to influence otheremotions.</p>
<h2 id="The-Take-Away"><a href="#The-Take-Away" class="headerlink" title="The Take Away"></a>The Take Away</h2><p>As a designer, you have three types of repetition:</p>
<ul>
<li>Repetition</li>
<li>Patterns</li>
<li>Rhythm</li>
</ul>
<p>You can use these toshape the user experience of your web or app. Through repetition,patterns, or rhythm, you set “the mood” of theuser interface and use these elements to either reinforce your message and/or create the look and feel of your product.</p>
<p>Repetition is the simplest element you can use. Pattern is a combination of elements that are repeated. Rhythm involves using intervals or spaces between elements to give the user an impression of rhythm or movement. We can use five types of rhythm:</p>
<ul>
<li>Random Rhythm</li>
<li>Regular Rhythm</li>
<li>Alternating Rhythm</li>
<li>Flowing Rhythm</li>
<li>Progressive Rhythm</li>
</ul>
<p>There is also another conception of pattern that comes from architect Christopher Alexander. We will examine that in a later article. Rhythm, like in music, helps build a cadence in your design, engaging your users with all sorts of interesting variations. With some thought, you can maximize the impact of your message by working the right rhythm into your design.</p>
<h2 id="References-amp-Where-to-Learn-More"><a href="#References-amp-Where-to-Learn-More" class="headerlink" title="References &amp; Where to Learn More"></a>References &amp; Where to Learn More</h2><ul>
<li>Hero Image: Author/Copyright holder: Jonas Bengtsson. Copyright terms and licence: CC BY 2.0</li>
<li>Design in Art: Repetition, Pattern, and Rhythm.<br>Sophia Learning.<br>Retrieved from: <a href="http://www.sophia.org/tutorials/design-in-art-repetition-pattern-and-rhythm" target="_blank" rel="external">http://www.sophia.org/tutorials/design-in-art-repetition-pattern-and-rhythm</a>. [2014, Aug]</li>
<li>Swinburne. BasicDesign Principles. Retrieved from: <a href="http://www.swinburne.edu.au/design/tutorials/design/design/\#four" target="_blank" rel="external">http://www.swinburne.edu.au/design/tutorials/design/design/\#four</a>. [2014 Aug]</li>
</ul>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/QfAJN3N" target="_blank" rel="external">https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/article/repetition-pattern-and-rhythm</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Let’s look at three subjects that, at first glance, may strike you as being incredibly basic and self-explanatory. However, although they
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Design. Prototype. Propose. How One Man Used Adobe XD To Ask ‘Will You Marry Me?’</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/design-prototype-propose-how-one-man-used-adobe-xd-to-ask-will-you-marry-me/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/design-prototype-propose-how-one-man-used-adobe-xd-to-ask-will-you-marry-me/</id>
    <published>2017-06-28T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-28T10:01:53.433Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Adobe XD is known as a powerful design and prototyping tool, but at its core it’s a communication tool that lets users share ideas quickly and easily. We’ve seen lots of examples of great work<a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23madewithadobexd&amp;src=typd" target="_blank" rel="external">shared online with #MadeWithAdobeXD</a>, but nothing quite like this. When Lee Chapman, a Latvia-based project manager for Cake HR, was introduced to XD by his boss, he started dreaming up a plan to use the program outside of work. It was a mission of love.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/zERZV3z.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Lee was dreaming up a creative way to propose to his girlfriend Zane (pronounced Zana), and he decided Adobe XD was going to be the way to do it.</p>
<p>“Zane and I met on Tinder, and I wanted her to relive the experience of our first date, so I decided to mock-up my own version of Tinder,” said Lee. The only problem — Lee isn’t a pro designer and had never used XD before, but that didn’t stop him! “I started on Monday and I proposed to her on Friday. That’s the amazing thing about XD, how quickly I could do this.” His first design and prototype was a milestone in many ways.</p>
<h3 id="The-Plan"><a href="#The-Plan" class="headerlink" title="The Plan"></a>The Plan</h3><p>Chapman spent nights working on his prototype, hiding the computer screen from Zane so she wouldn’t see what he was up to. Leveraging the prototyping power of XD, Lee created an immersive treasure hunt for Zane, mimicking the buttons and interactions of Tinder. The prototype led her from their home to the street corner where they first met, then on to the coffee shop where they had their first date. Lee simply wired up his design so each button interaction took her to a different screen, guiding her along the journey Chapman had planned.</p>
<p>“You could say I was able to quickly onboard her through the engagement experience. I quickly learned I could use the tool to direct her where I wanted her to go,” he said.</p>
<p>On Friday morning, after he had finished his design, Lee headed to work and sent Zane the link to his prototype, telling her to follow along with strict instructions not to skip ahead. She went on the journey, following the directions to locations and reading the love letters Chapman had composed on artboards throughout.</p>
<p>“The love letters detailed how our lives are going to be changing, and she told me while she was reading this in the middle of the street she was bawling her eyes out,” said Chapman.</p>
<p>As Zane was completing her treasure hunt throughout the city, Chapman was at home getting ready to ‘pop the question.’</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/7BZNfe2.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h3 id="The-Proposal"><a href="#The-Proposal" class="headerlink" title="The Proposal"></a>The Proposal</h3><p>The final screen in Chapman’s prototype led Zane back to their house.</p>
<p>“She let me know she was having the best time ever and crying her eyes out, and she was completely naive to what was next. It was also her birthday, so she thought it was her birthday present. She didn’t have any clue of the big finish until she came home,” he said.</p>
<p>That’s where Chapman was waiting in a tuxedo with flowers and a big question. He asked her to marry him.</p>
<p>“She said yes, and she loved the entire experience. To be honest, I think I nailed a pretty unique proposal.”</p>
<p>He calls his creation an MVP (minimum viable proposal) on a personal level, and says the end result felt like an immersive story, since it was so easy for Zane to use.</p>
<p>“I was able to give her that personal touch and that WOW moment throughout the whole experience, with every single push of a button.”</p>
<h3 id="Easy-to-Design-Prototype-and-Share"><a href="#Easy-to-Design-Prototype-and-Share" class="headerlink" title="Easy to Design, Prototype, and Share"></a>Easy to Design, Prototype, and Share</h3><p>Because Zane would be using the prototype on her own, Chapman wanted to make sure it worked perfectly on her phone as she travelled to ‘their spots’ in the city.</p>
<p>“XD provides artboard templates to her version of iPhone, so actually having the dimensions there was so helpful. What I also love and found super useful were the UI kits, like the one for Apple iOS, which made it easy to add in the default images for the mobile application design,” he said.</p>
<p>He also found it easy to create a working prototype that would give Zane the open feel of an app, but still guide her on the experience he wanted to create.</p>
<p>“I really loved how you can create a prototype with click functionality. My design was very basic, but that’s because Tinder is very basic, and I wanted to ensure the prototype I made gave the impression of a real application,” he said.</p>
<p>Chapman has lots of reasons to be excited. On top of getting married, he and Zane are expecting a child, and no doubt their son or daughter has a lot of Adobe XD treasure hunts to look forward to.</p>
<p>“On a personal level, this is experience has helped me on my journey to learning how to be a UX designer. I’m not the best at UI or UX, but I was able to open up my world to create that user experience that no one’s going to have.”</p>
<p><em>You can follow Lee Chapman’s work on</em><a href="http://twitter.com/leefranchap" target="_blank" rel="external"><em><strong>his Twitter</strong></em></a><em><strong>, and</strong></em><a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/experience-design.html" target="_blank" rel="external"><em><strong>click here to learn more about Adobe XD</strong></em></a><em><strong>and its powerful prototyping tools.</strong></em></p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/AJzQBjy" target="_blank" rel="external">https://blogs.adobe.com/creativecloud/design-prototype-propose-how-one-man-used-adobe-xd-to-ask-will-you-marry-me</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Adobe XD is known as a powerful design and prototyping tool, but at its core it’s a communication tool that lets users share ideas quickl
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>5 ways type can define brands</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/5-ways-type-can-define-brands/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/28/5-ways-type-can-define-brands/</id>
    <published>2017-06-28T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-28T10:01:53.415Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Choosing the right typeface is a crucial part of thelogo design process, but when it comes to defining the unique characteristics of a brand, it can also play a much more subtle role in shaping its personality and tone of voice.</p>
<p>For smaller brands, this tends to be as simple as selecting an existing typeface that’s best suited for their particular needs. But the ultimate solution, for those with the time and budget to do so, is a bespoke font tweaked to perfection.</p>
<p>Studios such as<a href="https://www.daltonmaag.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Dalton Maag</a>,<a href="https://commercialtype.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Commercial Type</a>,<a href="http://www.fontsmith.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Fontsmith</a>and<a href="https://www.typography.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hoefler &amp; Co</a>haver extensive experience in developing bespoke typefaces for brands, and many of their clients have honed their personality across many different platforms as a result.</p>
<p>Read on to discover how bespoke typography has enhanced brands across five different sectors…</p>
<h3 id="01-Motion-friendly-type-for-broadcasters"><a href="#01-Motion-friendly-type-for-broadcasters" class="headerlink" title="01. Motion-friendly type for broadcasters"></a>01. Motion-friendly type for broadcasters</h3><p>On-screen branding provides a particular challenge for bespoke typefaces, as motion graphics come into play alongside all manner of other uses, from billboards to corporate stationery.</p>
<p><a href="http://brody-associates.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Brody Associates</a>’ highly distinctive typeface for Channel 4 is a great example of the versatility required to convey personality in this field. Within the same family, it combines a functional text face (Chadwick) with a highly expressive display version (Horseferry).</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/fERJBbY.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Channel 4 can choose between text face Chadwick and display face Horseferry</p>
<p>Horseferry incorporates elements from Channel 4’s logo into the letterforms, with highly unconventional, striking results that can only function at large sizes, such as for advertising. Chadwick follows the same basic structure, but calms things down to help with legibility, particularly when used to communicate information on screen.</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/vy6Brm6.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>The curves of the ITV logotype are echoed in its typeface</p>
<p>For ITV, Fontsmith was given the task of translating the smooth, flowing curves of the broadcaster’s logotype into a whole typeface family to be used across the brand, including TV, online and on-demand applications.</p>
<p>The resulting typeface is detailed and wide proportioned, with a subtle calligraphic feel. According to Fontsmith: “When you take a pen off the page when writing, you get the sense of a rounded ending to the stroke or line creating a subtle, modern and bouncy script tone of voice.”</p>
<h3 id="02-Standout-typography-for-packaging"><a href="#02-Standout-typography-for-packaging" class="headerlink" title="02. Standout typography for packaging"></a>02. Standout typography for packaging</h3><p>When it comes to brands that express themselves on packaging, on-shelf standout becomes a critical factor to consider in a typeface. And where global brands are concerned, different language support also comes into play as that packaging needs to cater to different markets.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/Qj2eqeZ.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Colgate Ready was translated into a range of different scripts</p>
<p>Another Fontsmith case study is Colgate, in collaboration with The Partners and Red Fuse Communications. The brief was to reflect the “emotional and tonal dimensions” of the brand through a Roman/Latin typeface in three different weights, and ‘Colgate Ready’ was the result.</p>
<p>Colgate Ready was translated into Cyrillic, Eastern European, Devanagari and Thai, with a consistent stroke weight, x-height, cap height, width proportions and terminals.</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/2iQNR3f.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Hoefler &amp; Co’s bespoke typeface is used sparingly on Tiffany &amp; Co’s packaging</p>
<p>At the other end of the scale, in the luxury market, Tiffany &amp; Co’s unique typeface, created by Hoefler &amp; Co, is used sparingly on the jeweller’s minimalist packaging, making those iconic duck-egg-blue boxes even more desirable.</p>
<h3 id="03-Flexible-typography-for-retail"><a href="#03-Flexible-typography-for-retail" class="headerlink" title="03. Flexible typography for retail"></a>03. Flexible typography for retail</h3><p>Another fascinating application of bespoke type is in the retail space, where applications range from signage and wayfinding, to point-of-sale displays, to own-brand packaging.</p>
<p>Dalton Maag was commissioned to create a bespoke font for Lush, translating the boutique cosmetics brand’s distinctive chalkboard-style handwritten signage into a more neutral and contemporary typeface.</p>
<p>“Every letter had two alternate versions, while the most-used letters had three alternates,” explains designer Riccardo de Franceschi. “On top of these we created ligatures, and selected them according to not only frequency of use, but also the way the Lush handwriters write.”</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/q6NzAzr.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>For Lush’s typeface, each character needed two or three alternative versions</p>
<p>Lush’s typeface helps develop its boutique, artisan brand voice, but larger stores need to tread a finer line between personality and functionality – such as Fontsmith’s bespoke typeface for Sainsbury’s, which uses the foundry’s own FS Lola as a starting point.</p>
<p>“The new font needed to successfully stretch across a wide range of channels including above the line marketing, online, publications, packaging, in-store services, in-store navigation and in-store pricing,” reveals the agency. “It had to work from 400pt, all the way down to 6pt.”</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/NRzQbe6.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Sainsbury’s’ font needed to stretch across a wide range of uses</p>
<p>FS Lola’s distinctive slab serifs were softened, while regularly used brand words – particularly those that featured in wayfinding and signage – were adjusted on a case by case basis to improve legibility while conveying the supermarket’s personality.</p>
<h3 id="04-Scalable-typography-for-mobile"><a href="#04-Scalable-typography-for-mobile" class="headerlink" title="04. Scalable typography for mobile"></a>04. Scalable typography for mobile</h3><p>When it comes to mobile use, the need for functionality and legibility at tiny sizes on small screens can all too easily overwhelm brand personality. But it’s not impossible.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/EFVvQvq.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>For Nokia, Dalton Maag faced a massive, multi-platform, multi-language project</p>
<p>Bespoke type projects don’t get much more in-depth than Dalton Maag’s breakthrough project for global giant Nokia, which saw the agency expand massively to handle the demands of the multi-platform, multi-language project – including Hebrew, Arabic, Thai, Greek and Russian.</p>
<p>“This was all about going back to Finnish design roots – clean, simple, pure – and functionality was the primary objective,” explains Bruno Maag. “There was a big discussion about whether the brand fonts should have more personality or not. While the UI fonts need to be functional and readable, the display fonts have to do something else for their job.”</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/jURzmi6.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Fontsmith created this bespoke semi-slab serif typeface for Movistar</p>
<p>Fontsmith collaborated with Interbrand on a bespoke semi-slab serif typeface for Movistar, Telefónica’s Spanish and Latin American mobile operator. According to the agency: “We needed to be mindful that the slab wasn’t too static, that it had rhythm, progression, an approachable nature, and was authentic.”</p>
<h3 id="05-Apt-typography-for-editorial"><a href="#05-Apt-typography-for-editorial" class="headerlink" title="05. Apt typography for editorial"></a>05. Apt typography for editorial</h3><p>One of the most varied uses for a bespoke typeface is in a newspaper or magazine, purely because there are so many sizes, weights and styles involved in different capacities.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/INFbyaq.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Commercial Type designed this multi-weight typeface for The Guardian in 2005</p>
<p>A particularly high-profile example of this is Commercial Type’s multi-weight typeface for The Guardian, which coincided with the newspaper’s transition to the Berliner format in 2005. It has served the newspaper well ever since, although the recent announcement that it’ll shrink to tabloid size in 2018 may prompt another refresh.</p>
<p>The extensive family incorporates several interrelated families: an Egyptian for headlines; a Text Egyptian; four different widths of Sans for headlines; and finally an Agate Sans. Between them, they can handle everything from hard-hitting headlines to tiny financial listings.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/6R3mm2B.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Wired is synonymous with innovative typography</p>
<p>One magazine that’s synonymous with innovative use of type is Condé Nast’s Wired – and again, Hoefler &amp; Co rose to the challenge with Forza, an adaptable sans serif based on a rounded rectangle structure that, like Guardian Collection, is available commercially.</p>
<p>“Wired commissioned us to design a square sans as its editorial workhorse – one that could handle everything from philosophical essays to down-to-earth service pieces,” reports Hoefler &amp; Co. “Forza’s sophisticated visual vocabulary makes it alert and engaging, and its broad palette of weights ensures it can meet the needs of the most demanding designer.”</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/yIzmAnr" target="_blank" rel="external">http://www.creativebloq.com/features/5-ways-type-can-define-brands</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Choosing the right typeface is a crucial part of thelogo design process, but when it comes to defining the unique characteristics of a br
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>iOS 11 beta has iPhone secrets</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/ios-11-beta-has-iphone-secrets/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/ios-11-beta-has-iphone-secrets/</id>
    <published>2017-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-27T09:28:23.935Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>TheiPhone 8 could end up being an amazing, transformative 10th-anniversaryiPhone. At first glance,iOS 11 doesn’t seem quite so ambitious. It’s more of a series of targeted upgrades, with some of them being downright fantastic. </p>
<p>Apple’s newest version of its operating system for iPhones and iPads doesn’t formally arrive until later this year, but it’s here in public beta form now. You can install it on your own iPads and iPhones, if you dare. Don’t do so on your primary device, however, only experiment with it on a secondary device, and be ready for plenty of bugs. Betas do weird things sometimes and App Store apps aren’t optimized for it yet anyway.</p>
<p>I’ve already been using it for a few days, testing it on aniPhone 7 Plus (for this story) and a new 10.5-inchiPad Pro (to see all the extra features it adds on theiPad). With the caveat that this is a beta – and not a feature-complete one at that – here are my first impressions.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnet.com/pictures/ios-11-beta-iphone-ipad-features/" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/YbuumyA.jpg!web" alt="">36iOS 11’s best features for iPhone and iPad</a></p>
<h3 id="The-killer-features"><a href="#The-killer-features" class="headerlink" title="The killer features:"></a>The killer features:</h3><h4 id="You-can-pluck-the-best-shots-from-Live-Photos"><a href="#You-can-pluck-the-best-shots-from-Live-Photos" class="headerlink" title="You can pluck the best shots from Live Photos"></a>You can pluck the best shots from Live Photos</h4><p>When Live Photos first launched in 2015, they seemed clever but gimmicky. My brother-in-law asked me back then, can Live Photo pick another shot to grab a moment you thought you missed? It couldn’t before, but it can now. Editing a Live Photo now allows any of the shots to become the “primary photo.” Missed your kid’s smile? Maybe you didn’t. It’s now a time machine for snapshots and a backup plan. I’m never turning it off after the iOS 11 upgrade. Added GIF-like loop effects and a nice long exposure trick are great too, but nothing beats editable shots.</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/NRvAJra.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Pick your best shot.</p>
<p>Sarah Tew/CNET</p>
<h4 id="A-one-page-Control-Center"><a href="#A-one-page-Control-Center" class="headerlink" title="A one-page Control Center"></a>A one-page Control Center</h4><p>The iPhone’s handy swipe-up panel sprawled into a weird multi-page monster withiOS 10, but it fits on one pane in iOS 11. New features are added, too, and shortcuts to key apps can be added or removed like widgets. Nice adds are Notes, Voice Memo and a greatApple TV remote tool built-in. I can keep my lost Apple TV remote wedged in the sofa permanently. Still, it could have added even more. Control Center doesn’t use 3D Touch as much as I thought it would to deep-dive further in settings. But, hey, it’s progress.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/ArY32u3.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Control Center has sub-sections, now.</p>
<p>Sarah Tew/CNET</p>
<h4 id="Screen-recording"><a href="#Screen-recording" class="headerlink" title="Screen recording"></a>Screen recording</h4><p>It’s not going to be for everyone, but it’s so easy to start recording what you do on your iPhone, even add voice-over commentary and share as a video. How-to videos and self-help sites are going to benefit tremendously. Maybe I’d use this to show my mom how to adjust her phone settings the next time she calls – I could just email the video.</p>
<h4 id="Marking-up-almost-anything"><a href="#Marking-up-almost-anything" class="headerlink" title="Marking up (almost) anything"></a>Marking up (almost) anything</h4><p>The next time you want to share what you see on your iPhone (or iPad), remember that screenshots (home plus the power button together) now launch a markup tool that lets you scribble or highlight anything. Well, almost anything… movies and protected videos ended up blacked out (on iOS 10, that doesn’t happen). Circle a weird comment, add a note with your finger. Safari has a “markup as PDF” feature that does the same thing. It’ll be great for Twitter or Facebook. In a similar vein, PDFs are easy to make and even add signatures to.</p>
<h4 id="A-built-in-scanner-in-Notes"><a href="#A-built-in-scanner-in-Notes" class="headerlink" title="A built-in scanner in Notes"></a>A built-in scanner in Notes</h4><p>Apple’s Notes app keeps getting serious upgrades, pushing it further into Evernote country. Tables can be added in iOS 11, and there’s also a scanning tool to add receipts or other documents. It does a pretty good job stretching and evening out off-angle scans, but it doesn’t convert into editable text.</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/uQfUfiq.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>One-handed keyboard!</p>
<p>Sarah Tew/CNET</p>
<h3 id="Some-other-things-to-try"><a href="#Some-other-things-to-try" class="headerlink" title="Some other things to try:"></a>Some other things to try:</h3><h4 id="Siri-sounds-different-and-can-translate"><a href="#Siri-sounds-different-and-can-translate" class="headerlink" title="Siri sounds different and can translate"></a>Siri sounds different and can translate</h4><p>Siri is supposed to be somewhat smarter now. I didn’t see a giant boost yet, but Siri definitely sounds different. The “more natural” style actually threw me off a bit. Siri’s nicest new feature is instant audio translation into French, German, Italian, Mandarin Chinese and Spanish. It’s in beta – so be wary of relying on it in a serious setting – but it’s nice to have at a quick button press. (Google Translate is still my go-to, though.)</p>
<h4 id="One-handed-keyboards"><a href="#One-handed-keyboards" class="headerlink" title="One-handed keyboards"></a>One-handed keyboards</h4><p>A little iOS 11 trick is to press and hold the “emoji” button in the keyboard to get a new left- or right-hand-squished keyboard optimized for one-handed typing. It’s reminiscent of the old compressed keyboard on theiPhone SE.</p>
<h4 id="The-Files-app"><a href="#The-Files-app" class="headerlink" title="The Files app"></a>The Files app</h4><p>There’s now a place to consolidate folders and apps locally or in cloud accounts. It’s taking some getting used to in the beta, but it’s finally a central place to dump your stuff. But, so far, I found I couldn’t just instantly make folders on my iPhone without putting them into pre-existing folders… which is disappointing.</p>
<h4 id="Portrait-mode-for-7-Plus-gets-flash-HDR-effects"><a href="#Portrait-mode-for-7-Plus-gets-flash-HDR-effects" class="headerlink" title="Portrait mode for 7 Plus gets flash/HDR/effects"></a>Portrait mode for 7 Plus gets flash/HDR/effects</h4><p>Extra camera modes mean Portrait mode’s bokeh-type effects can be used in more situations.</p>
<h4 id="‘Do-Not-Disturb-While-Driving’"><a href="#‘Do-Not-Disturb-While-Driving’" class="headerlink" title="‘Do Not Disturb While Driving’"></a>‘Do Not Disturb While Driving’</h4><p>At long last, iPhones have a new filter to remove messages while driving. It’s a more targeted variation of “Do Not Disturb.” It can be triggered automatically, manually or while connected to a car’s Bluetooth, and it also auto-replies to contacts (or only some of them) to let them know you’re driving. I haven’t used this a ton yet, but I’m curious.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/byEjiiR.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>OK.</p>
<p>Sarah Tew/CNET</p>
<h3 id="Not-so-hot"><a href="#Not-so-hot" class="headerlink" title="Not so hot:"></a>Not so hot:</h3><h4 id="The-new-App-Store"><a href="#The-new-App-Store" class="headerlink" title="The new App Store"></a>The new App Store</h4><p>Apple’s redesign of the store feels likeApple Music, Apple News and many recent redesigned parts of iOS. After a few days in it, I’m not sure it’s easier to discover what I’m looking for. There are a lot more Apple-curated lists, it seems, and articles written about featured apps by Apple’s editorial staff. Games are split off from the rest of the App Store to allow other apps to be featured better. Does it make things better? </p>
<h4 id="Added-Siri-suggestions-in-News-and-other-things"><a href="#Added-Siri-suggestions-in-News-and-other-things" class="headerlink" title="Added Siri suggestions in News and other things"></a>Added Siri suggestions in News and other things</h4><p>Supposedly, Apple News makes suggestions from what you’re looking for in Safari. I haven’t seen that emerge for me yet. Quick-type suggestions in Safari’s keyboard bring up more specific things, often based on what you’re looking at. But not always, and I found some oddities.</p>
<h3 id="What-you-don’t-get-yet-but-will-eventually"><a href="#What-you-don’t-get-yet-but-will-eventually" class="headerlink" title="What you don’t get yet (but will eventually):"></a>What you don’t get yet (but will eventually):</h3><h4 id="Augmented-reality"><a href="#Augmented-reality" class="headerlink" title="Augmented reality"></a>Augmented reality</h4><p>Apple’s<a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/apples-first-crack-at-ar-looks-surprisingly-good/" target="_blank" rel="external">amazing ARKit</a>doesn’t have any apps or demos to show off in this beta, so you’ll have to wait for software developers to show their stuff in the fall… or watch<a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/apples-amazing-looking-ar-could-also-be-super-sharable/" target="_blank" rel="external">developer experiments</a>online.</p>
<p>Source: “<a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/3EFbIvm" target="_blank" rel="external">https://www.cnet.com/news/ios-11-public-beta-what-it-does-for-the-iphone/</a>“</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;TheiPhone 8 could end up being an amazing, transformative 10th-anniversaryiPhone. At first glance,iOS 11 doesn’t seem quite so ambitious.
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>With Alphabet, Google faces a daunting challenge: organizing itself</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/the-holy-wars-of-procrastination/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/the-holy-wars-of-procrastination/</id>
    <published>2017-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-27T09:28:23.938Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SAN FRANCISCOGoogle’s self-professed mission is to organize the world’s information. But a company known for engineering excellence is still trying to solve the very human problem of how to organize itself.</p>
<p>Nearly two years ago, Google co-founder Larry Page announced the tech giant would be remade as Alphabet, a holding company whose units would include Google and an array of unrelated pursuits in areas such as healthcare, self-driving cars and urban planning.</p>
<p>Wall Street cheered. Previously those riskier ventures had been lumped into Google’s overall financial results. Investors would now see Google’s performance independent of its so-called “Other Bets,” an eclectic collection of 11 ventures. They include Nest, a maker of Wi-Fi enabled thermostats; Calico, which seeks to prolong the human lifespan; and X, the company’s secretive research lab.</p>
<p>Alphabet’s top management also aimed to boost accountability by appointing chief executives to head each of the Other Bets. Few people in Google’s constellation of ventures had ever held the title prior to that.</p>
<p>But so far Alphabet has failed to show it can convert its Other Bets from experiments to businesses with the reach, impact and money-making potential of Google’s core search and advertising operations. Interviews with two dozen former Alphabet executives and employees reveal an organization grappling with how much time and resources Other Bets deserve in the pursuit of profitability.</p>
<p>In the first quarter, which ended March 31, the ventures lost a combined $855 million; that’s on top of a collective $3.6 billion loss for 2016. As a whole, Alphabet generated $90.3 billion in revenue in 2016. Google’s share of that revenue was $89.5 billion, while its 2016 operating income was $27.9 billion.</p>
<p>Alphabet’s early days have seen more pruning than expansion of its holdings.</p>
<p>The company has skinned back plans for Google Fiber, which delivers rapid Internet service in 10 metro areas. This month, Alphabet agreed to sell robotics company Boston Dynamics to Japanese multinational SoftBank Group Corp. It unloaded its Terra Bella satellite imaging business in February.</p>
<p>At one point last year, it was even looking to sell Nest, the largest of the Other Bets, three people familiar with the matter told Reuters. Google paid an eye-popping $3.2 billion for the start-up in 2014.</p>
<p>(For a graphic showing Alphabet’s holdings, see:<a href="http://tmsnrt.rs/2rNgdKN" target="_blank" rel="external">tmsnrt.rs/2rNgdKN</a>)</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a series of executives have departed since the reorganization, including the heads of Nest, an Internet operation called Access and a venture capital firm known as GV.</p>
<p>An Alphabet spokeswoman declined repeated requests for comment or to make executives available for interviews. Supporters of the restructuring frame the early struggles as typical growing pains.</p>
<p>For now, Wall Street isn’t worried: Alphabet’s stock is near an all-time high, having reached $1,000 per share in June. Ruth Porat, the no-nonsense chief financial officer who has steered the restructuring, has won rave reviews from investors for enforcing financial accountability across Alphabet.</p>
<p>Some Other Bets have made notable strides. Life sciences initiative Verily recently attracted $800 million in outside investment. Self-driving car project Waymo is considered among the leaders in the burgeoning industry.</p>
<p>Still, it’s not yet clear the structure will enable Alphabet to do what most companies cannot: conceive the next wave of innovation in-house or through the development of key acquisitions. That goal is central to both the company’s mission and investor expectations, analysts say.</p>
<p>“The reason Google gets to trade at a decent multiple… is because there’s a growth story beyond advertising,” said analyst James Wang of ARK Investment Management.</p>
<p>CEO or COO?</p>
<p>The Alphabet structure is Google’s stab at an age-old corporate conundrum: sustaining innovation within a giant enterprise.</p>
<p>Alphabet’s strategy is to give entrepreneurs the autonomy of a startup, coupled with the discipline of a traditional corporate structure.</p>
<p>Roughly once a quarter, Other Bets leaders meet with the Alphabet board – comprised of Porat, Page, Google co-founder Sergey Brin and David Drummond, Alphabet’s senior vice president of corporate development – to discuss funding and performance, according to two former employees.</p>
<p>At the same time, Alphabet is establishing separate compensation plans for the Other Bets to reward employees if their ventures succeed, mirroring startup incentives.</p>
<p>The formula has primed Alphabet’s emerging businesses for “global impact,” Alphabet Executive Chairman Eric Schmidt said this month at the annual stockholders meeting at the Mountain View headquarters.</p>
<p>“There is one solution that we know works well in capitalism, which is boards, shareholders, CEOs,” Schmidt said. “My bet is that the traditional lessons of business organization will in fact result in success at Alphabet.”</p>
<p>Still, Alphabet top brass continue to hold sway over key strategy and financing decisions, a dynamic that has chafed Other Bets chief executives who’ve complained they are treated more like chief operating officers than shot callers, according to people familiar with the situation.</p>
<p>In addition, scrutiny from Wall Street limits how generous Alphabet can be in extending Google’s resources to Other Bets, said Brian McClendon, a former vice president of engineering at Google.</p>
<p>“As of yet, the restructuring hasn’t provided what I think is one of the immediate benefits, which is risk-taking investment,” he said.</p>
<p>NICKELED AND DIMED</p>
<p>Some companies acquired by Google found that being part of Alphabet wasn’t what they’d bargained for.</p>
<p>Two former Nest employees said they were promised generous funding and time to achieve profitability following the company’s acquisition by Google in 2014. But after the restructuring, Alphabet executives were keenly focused on revenue, one former employee said.</p>
<p>Pricey overhead has made the path to profitability tougher. After the restructuring, Alphabet began charging Other Bets for their portion of shared services such as security and facilities, ending what had previously amounted to a subsidy, people familiar with the situation said. The units also felt pressure to maintain Google perks such as free employee meals.</p>
<p>“One of the pitfalls (of Alphabet) is that those companies are asked to stand on their own two feet, but they may inherit the cost structure of Google,” said Nest investor Peter Nieh, a partner at Lightspeed Venture Partners.</p>
<p>In early 2016, Alphabet explored selling Nest in an effort code-named Project Amalfi, according to three people familiar with the matter. No deal materialized, and Nest co-founder Tony Fadell departed last year. Fadell declined to comment.</p>
<p>Boston Dynamics, acquired in 2013 during a robotics shopping spree led by Android creator Andy Rubin, enjoyed generous funding at first. But it was adrift after Rubin’s departure, two former employees said. Rubin did not respond to requests for comment.</p>
<p>GRUMPY GOOGLERS</p>
<p>The creation of the Other Bets has also changed what it means to work for Google.</p>
<p>Some grumble that their role now is to subsidize innovation at their sister companies, rather than to innovate themselves.</p>
<p>“It did sort of send the message to people who stayed back at Google, whether in search or in ads: Your job isn’t to push the envelope,” one former Googler said.</p>
<p>Employee transfers to X, the illustrious “moonshot factory,” are more complicated now that it’s a separate entity, former employees say.</p>
<p>That’s a striking shift, especially for high-performing employees accustomed to moving about the company almost at will, said Punit Soni, a former Google employee who is now chief executive of Learning Motors, an artificial intelligence startup.</p>
<p>“A basic premise of Google was people could do whatever they wanted,” Soni said. “I can see why people will feel like it’s no longer the old Google.”</p>
<p>In the meantime, co-founder Page is pursuing yet another “moonshot”: flying cars.</p>
<p>He is the primary investor in Kitty Hawk, a startup in the field that is entirely outside the Alphabet umbrella.</p>
<p>(Editing by Marla Dickerson)</p>
<p>Source:<a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/RvMJZ3B" target="_blank" rel="external">http://www.reuters.com/article/us-alphabet-tensions-insight-idUSKBN19I0G9?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews&amp;utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed: reuters/technologyNews (Reuters Technology News)</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;SAN FRANCISCOGoogle’s self-professed mission is to organize the world’s information. But a company known for engineering excellence is st
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bad Ideas Are The Key To Creativity</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/bad-ideas-are-the-key-to-creativity/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/bad-ideas-are-the-key-to-creativity/</id>
    <published>2017-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-27T09:28:23.931Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Growing up, we’re all taught to follow the rules. Wait your turn in line. Fill in the bubble of the right answer. Eat your dessert last. Tie your shoes and tuck your shirt in. Don’t ask stupid questions. We’re rewarded for caution and deliberation, punished for<a href="https://www.inc.com/sonia-thompson/want-to-raise-a-confident-girl-encourage-her-to-be-a-little-bad.html" target="_blank" rel="external">coloring outside the lines</a>.</p>
<p>Over time, we’re shuffled into groups based on test results and pursue careers based on our credentials and degrees. We eventually file into offices where we are required to dress a certain way, talk a certain way; behave a certain way. At some point along this journey, the world designates you as “creative” or “non-creative” with most people falling into the latter category.</p>
<p>And yet, we know that creative thinking is necessary for success. It has enabled the rise and sustainable success of companies like Airbnb, Facebook and Uber; completely transforming industries like hospitality, advertising and transportation. In fact,<a href="https://www-03.ibm.com/press/us/en/pressrelease/31670.wss" target="_blank" rel="external">an IBM study</a>of 1,500 CEOs found that creativity was considered the most essential feature of their organization, more than integrity or even vision. According to the CEOs, creativity enables companies to navigate today’s increasingly complex business environment.</p>
<p>The secret to creativity, according to science: persistence.</p>
<p>There are many reasons why we, as a society, abandon creative thinking as we enter adulthood. For one, creativity is messy and uncertain; it goes against everything we learn along the way in formal education and through socialization. Creative thinking can be scary because it makes us vulnerable to judgment and can sometimes feel like we’re giving up control. That’s why many people reassign themselves to the non-creative category – they repress their creative potential in exchange for structure, conformity and comfort.</p>
<p>The notion that individuals are inherently “creative” or “non-creative” is a dangerous one. It implies that only certain people are gifted with creativity, which has beendisproved by loads of research, including one<a href="http://psycnet.apa.org/journals/psp/109/2/232/" target="_blank" rel="external">study</a>from Northwestern University.</p>
<p>The research suggests we give up too easily when confronted with a problem that requires creative thinking. What’s more, the research finds the most creative ideas tend to arise after many others have been considered and discarded, proving that the key to creative thought is to just keep at it.</p>
<h2 id="Bad-ideas-are-building-blocks-to-great-ones"><a href="#Bad-ideas-are-building-blocks-to-great-ones" class="headerlink" title="Bad ideas are building blocks to great ones."></a>Bad ideas are building blocks to great ones.</h2><p>There are two reasons why embracing bad ideas is necessary for great ones:</p>
<ol>
<li>Ideas that solve a problem in a unique way are usually a combination of existing ideas, many of which may seem bad at first.</li>
<li>Accepting that most of your ideas will be bad will help you move on to new ideas faster and more easily.</li>
</ol>
<p>Ultimately, like most things, creative thought is a trial-and-error process that requires failure. And while bad ideas can be building blocks to creative thought, sometimes they are in fact actually good ideas – just ones that nobody else understands yet.</p>
<p>Ideas that were once ridiculed have led to some of the greatest inventions in history, such as like human flight or electricity.</p>
<h2 id="Design-Thinking-is-a-great-technique-to-boost-creativity"><a href="#Design-Thinking-is-a-great-technique-to-boost-creativity" class="headerlink" title="Design Thinking is a great technique to boost creativity."></a>Design Thinking is a great technique to boost creativity.</h2><p>Used by Apple,<a href="http://www.gv.com/sprint/" target="_blank" rel="external">Google</a>, Samsung, and GE, Design Thinking has become an increasingly popular problem solving<a href="https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/article/what-is-design-thinking-and-why-is-it-so-popular" target="_blank" rel="external">approach</a>not just in design, but in business.</p>
<p>At it’s core, Design Thinking boils down to defining a problem and creating as many solutions as possible in a limited period of time. It is a technique that’s highly conducive for creativity because, like creative thought, it’s also a trial-and-error process; it’s rooted in generating a high-volume of ideas.</p>
<p>To give you a better idea of how you can leverage Design Thinking to create a new offering or improve upon existing ones, here is a 7-step crash course you can use immediately:</p>
<p>Step 1. Listen to your customers.First and foremost, get out of the office and talk to your users or customers, observe everyday tendencies of what they do, how they think, and what they want_outside<em>of the context of your company. The goal is to gather enough observations that you can start to write down problem statements such as</em>“Samantha dreads scheduling doctor’s appointments. How might we help her schedule appointments more easily?”_</p>
<p>Step2. Create visual representations of wild ideas using comic strips.Really. Using the problem statement in Step 1, describe possible solutions using illustrated narratives like comic book strips. Use stick figures to describe the scene in which Samantha would schedule doctor’s appointments in a new way. Sketch out 8 comic strips in 5 minutes, then spend 5 minutes sketching out one big comic strip idea, with each strip containing a different idea. Take a break and do it again.</p>
<p>Step 3. Imagine your new offering in the headlines.This will help you articulate new value propositions. Sketch out your favorite business magazine covers and draw cover images and headlines of what everyone will say about your new offering. For example, based on your comic strips you imagined booking an appointment using Siri, the headline in Inc Magazine might read_”How This Company Helps You Book a Doctor’s Appointment In Just a Few Words.”_Try to draw 10 copies in 10 minutes, take a break and repeat the 10 minute cycle. You can also feel free to describe ideas that you didn’t sketch in Step 2.</p>
<p>Step 4. Eliminate the impossible (not the bad).Once you’ve gone through all the ideas on the table, talk through ideas that you think would would be valuable and eliminate ideas that can’t be pursued immediately, like your doctor visiting your home via holograms. You should be able to combine ideas and narrow them down to 3 new ideas. This usually takes anywhere from a few hours to a full day.</p>
<p>Step 5. Make something you can touch and feel.The goal here is to evaluate an idea, not launch it. Be as resourceful as you can and try to limit yourself to only an hour to make a physical or digital prototype. A good starting point for simulating physical products is glue and popsicle stick, and tools like InVision or light code for digital ones. As long as you can touch it, anything goes.</p>
<p>Step 6. Then put it in the hands of your customers.Your customers are likely more imaginative than you think. Get a focus group together, show them what you made and get some knee-jerk reactions. The rule of thumb is to talk to 5-7 people to get the most insight in as little time as possible.</p>
<p>Step 7. Go back to the drawing board.Remember, the purpose of all the work you’ve put in to this point is to generate new ideas. If you think your customers are excited about your prototypes, start putting a plan together to execute on what you’ve created. If not, take the new learnings and go back to Step 1.</p>
<p>The beauty of this approach is you can do it in one week or over the course of 6 months, with most of the variability being in how much time you spend making your prototypes. It can be used by any department or role in the company to to unlock the creative potential across your entire organization.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/IRBjUju" target="_blank" rel="external">https://www.inc.com/yazin-akkawi/bad-ideas-are-the-key-to-creativity.html</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Growing up, we’re all taught to follow the rules. Wait your turn in line. Fill in the bubble of the right answer. Eat your dessert last. 
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>7 hot illustration trends of 2017 to make your project stand out</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/7-hot-illustration-trends-of-2017-to-make-your-project-stand-out/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/7-hot-illustration-trends-of-2017-to-make-your-project-stand-out/</id>
    <published>2017-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-27T09:28:23.928Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The world of illustration is constantly changing. And while we’d never encourage you to unthinkingly follow trends, it’s good to stay alert to the direction in which the creative world is moving.</p>
<p>So in this post, we’ll look at some of the biggest illustration trends to come our way in 2017 so far. But if you’re not an illustrator yourself, don’t worry; you can still get on board.</p>
<p><a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fstock-illustrations" target="_blank" rel="external">iStock by Getty Images</a>has a huge range of high-quality, low-cost and royalty-free illustrations, created by talented professionals, to quickly and easily download and use in your designs. </p>
<p>We’ve featured some examples in this post: just click on the image to find it on the site. Alternatively, head<a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fstock-illustrations" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>to see all the illustrations<a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com" target="_blank" rel="external">iStock by Getty Images</a>has to offer, and use the site’s powerful search functionality to find exactly what you’re looking for.</p>
<h3 id="01-Flat-and-minimal"><a href="#01-Flat-and-minimal" class="headerlink" title="01. Flat and minimal"></a>01. Flat and minimal</h3><p><a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fvector%2Fvector-trendy-minimalistic-red-fox-head-icon-in-polygonal-style-gm679856450-124564055%09%0A" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/vyayMrN.jpg!web" alt="">Vector trendy minimalistic red fox in polygonal style, by TechDesignWork. This illustration could be used, for example, as a menu icon on an animal welfare or animal rights website</a></p>
<p>Flat design has been the big graphics trend of the 2010s, and illustrators have followed in its wake, creating increasingly minimal, pixel-perfect vectorised art to match.</p>
<p>Magoz, Anna Kövecses, Sergio Membrillas, Malika Favre and Rob Bailey are amongst the illustrators creating inspiring and original work using this approach.</p>
<p>With strong emphasis on reduction and subtraction, these kind of illustrations are able to cross language and cultural barriers to convey a subject instantly and clearly. And in a world dominated by mobile devices and high-resolution screens, the demand for flat and minimal illustration is unlikely to go away anytime soon.</p>
<h3 id="02-Abstract-and-zen"><a href="#02-Abstract-and-zen" class="headerlink" title="02. Abstract and zen"></a>02. Abstract and zen</h3><p><a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fvector%2Fornate-circular-mandala-multicolored-designs-gm604349222-103770285" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/fYFJZr2.jpg!web" alt="">Ornate Circular Mandala Multicolored Design by Jennifer Borton. This illustration could be used, for example, as a background texture on a yoga and meditation website</a></p>
<p>The world of 2016-2017 has been a chaotic one in which old certainties have been overturned and uncomfortable new realities are starting to sink in. So it’s not surprising that there’s been a trend in illustration towards more relaxing, spiritually inspired patterns and imagery.</p>
<p>Influenced by Buddhism, Hinduism and abstract religious art in general, this kind of zen illustration acts as a philosophical comfort blanket in a rapidly changing and divided world.</p>
<h3 id="03-Hand-drawn-geometrics"><a href="#03-Hand-drawn-geometrics" class="headerlink" title="03. Hand-drawn geometrics"></a>03. Hand-drawn geometrics</h3><p><a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fvector%2Fvector-seamless-pattern-with-ink-circle-textures-abstract-seamless-background-with-gm694120898-128302289%09%0A" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/Zfyumqn.jpg!web" alt="">Vector seamless pattern with ink circle textures by Utro Na More. This illustration could be used, for example, as the background for a book cover design</a></p>
<p>Geometric illustration has been a popular trend throughout the decade, but recently we’ve seen a move away from the clinical, digital vector approach and a softening of the style through the incorporation of hand-drawn elements.</p>
<p>This kind of illustration combines the brain-delighting qualities of mathematically-based patterns with the spirit and beauty of physical drawing and painting, to create images that are alluring, inviting and potentially quite magical.</p>
<h3 id="04-Tattoo-art"><a href="#04-Tattoo-art" class="headerlink" title="04. Tattoo art"></a>04. Tattoo art</h3><p><a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fvector%2Fblue-phoenix-art-gm670133472-122538917%0A" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/zEVBjeQ.jpg!web" alt="">Blue phoenix art by Stereohype. This illustration could be used, for example, as a graphical element on a festival poster or program</a></p>
<p>You may have noticed that these days, almost everyone under the age of 25 is covered in tattoos. No longer just for those who walk on the wild side, tattoos have entered the mainstream, with their designs become increasingly expressive and beautiful.</p>
<p>Now popular tattoo styles are crossing over into the world of illustration too. Their influence can be seen in the work of creatives as diverse as Elena Gumeniuk, Daniel Mackie and Ollie Munden, while tattooists who’ve crossed over into full-blown illustration include Nomi Chi, Shawn Barber and Tim Lehi.</p>
<h3 id="05-Illustrative-icons"><a href="#05-Illustrative-icons" class="headerlink" title="05. Illustrative icons"></a>05. Illustrative icons</h3><p><a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fvector%2Foktoberfest-beer-icon-sign-illustration-gm693409416-128051075" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/iIRRRbR.jpg!web" alt="">Oktoberfest beer icon sign by pseudodaemon. With Oktoberfest-themed events taking place around the world, this illustration could work well as a hero image on an event-specific app</a></p>
<p>Once, computer icons were just tiny, basic shapes made of just a few pixels. In recent years, however, rapidly increasing levels of resolution on even the smallest screens means there’s been in an explosion in demand for more sophisticated designs.</p>
<p>Illustrators have followed suit, creating high resolution icons that make strong use of colour and complexity, while holding true to the fundamental purpose of an icon: to immediately convey a concept in a simple and easy-to-understand way.</p>
<h3 id="06-Multiple-exposure"><a href="#06-Multiple-exposure" class="headerlink" title="06. Multiple exposure"></a>06. Multiple exposure</h3><p><a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fvector%2Fmultiple-exposure-of-woman-and-trees-gm689165604-127201521" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/IRJvInA.jpg!web" alt="">Multiple exposure of woman and trees by George Peters. This illustration could be used, for example, on a flyer for a rock band</a></p>
<p>Creative disciplines have always borrowed from each other, and today’s creatives are getting more multidisciplinary than ever. Consequently, one of the latest trend we’ve spotted takes an idea from the world of photography (multiple exposures) and transfers it to the world of illustration. When done right, this collage-style approach offers a great way to evoke a combination of thoughts and feelings in the viewer, in an eye-catching, emotionally engaging way.</p>
<h3 id="07-Vivid-colour"><a href="#07-Vivid-colour" class="headerlink" title="07. Vivid colour"></a>07. Vivid colour</h3><p><a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fvector%2Fcolorful-humming-birds-and-rainbow-gm119958960-15439504" target="_blank" rel="external"><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/qUBBryY.jpg!web" alt="">Colourful humming birds and rainbow by Cienpies. This illustration could be used, for example, to help illustrate a children’s book or leaflet</a></p>
<p>With creatives looking to brighten up an increasingly dark and divided world in 2017, vivid colour has been everywhere. Evident in the work of Nejc Prah, Jack Sachs, Dominic Kesterton, Sebastian Curi, and others, vivid doesn’t necessarily mean primary, but it does mean in-your-face, mood brightening hues that can’t fail to grab the public’s attention. And that can be invaluable when incorporating an illustration into your design, whether that’s for print or online.</p>
<h3 id="Make-your-visuals-stand-out"><a href="#Make-your-visuals-stand-out" class="headerlink" title="Make your visuals stand out"></a>Make your visuals stand out</h3><p>Whatever kind of creative project you’re involved in, visuals are key to its success. Our brains process images 60,000 times faster than text and so making sure your images stand out is essential.</p>
<p>At<a href="http://istockphoto.7eer.net/c/247618/258824/4205?sharedid=june_advertoriaI&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.istockphoto.com%2Fgb%2Fstock-illustrations" target="_blank" rel="external">iStock by Getty Images</a>, you’ll find millions of authentic illustrations, and they even offer a free illustration to download each week. And the best news is, once you’ve found the perfect visual for your project, Creative Bloq readers can get a 10 per cent off discount with code CBTEN.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/iYZ7R3Z" target="_blank" rel="external">http://www.creativebloq.com/features/7-hot-illustration-trends-of-2017-to-make-your-project-stand-out</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The world of illustration is constantly changing. And while we’d never encourage you to unthinkingly follow trends, it’s good to stay ale
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>10 Ways to Design Menus That Don’t Suck</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/10-ways-to-design-menus-that-dont-suck/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/27/10-ways-to-design-menus-that-dont-suck/</id>
    <published>2017-06-27T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-27T09:28:23.889Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are definite right and wrong ways to design navigation menus. This basic part of a website is often overlooked in the design process and it shows in terms of usability.</p>
<p>Clunky, overcrowded or missing navigation are the most common issues and quite frankly they can make your website simply suck. Don’t be that guy (or girl). Use these tips to ensure that you are using modern navigation patterns in your website projects for cool, creative navigation elements that don’t suck. (And are highly usable.)</p>
<h2 id="1-Ditch-the-Mega-Menus"><a href="#1-Ditch-the-Mega-Menus" class="headerlink" title="1. Ditch the Mega Menus"></a>1. Ditch the Mega Menus</h2><p>Mega menus was a design fad that clients loved—even when designers hated it. The oversized menu style that includes “everything but the kitchen sink” is overwhelming to users and doesn’t provide any real value.</p>
<p>Only a handful of major retailers can really get away with using mega menus, and the purpose there is to show scale of inventory. The usefulness of the overloaded navigation element is questionable.</p>
<p>Often, a mega menu option is selected because it is too hard to narrow down what to put in the navigation. Make the tough choices. Dig in analytics to see what users are looking for. Honestly, most users who want a very specific thing will find it using search anyway.</p>
<p><img src="http://img2.tuicool.com/RzYZNna.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="2-Make-Search-Prominent"><a href="#2-Make-Search-Prominent" class="headerlink" title="2. Make Search Prominent"></a>2. Make Search Prominent</h2><p>And speaking of search: Make it prominent. Search should be on every page. It should in in the main navigation. And it should be large and easy to access.</p>
<p>Superb search functionality is the link that will keep users on a website. If what they are looking for isn’t readily available, the next option is likely to search for it. (You can thank Google for this search-first thought process.)</p>
<p>Don’t try to fight it. Work with users and include search as part of the main navigation. (And make sure the box is big enough to type, and fully see, common phrases into.)</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/JJ73aur.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="3-Limit-the-Number-of-Navigation-Choices"><a href="#3-Limit-the-Number-of-Navigation-Choices" class="headerlink" title="3. Limit the Number of Navigation Choices"></a>3. Limit the Number of Navigation Choices</h2><p>It’s your job to anticipate what content users will want to access next. Limit navigation choices to the most popular pages and information in the website design.</p>
<p>Almost every navigation menu should include search, an about or contact page and e-commerce sites should always include a cart or buy now button. After that navigation elements should be driven by site content.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/nAJj6nR.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="4-Develop-Smart-Navigation-Menus"><a href="#4-Develop-Smart-Navigation-Menus" class="headerlink" title="4. Develop Smart Navigation Menus"></a>4. Develop Smart Navigation Menus</h2><p>Good navigation will help users move from one bit of content to the next logical point. This content is often different on different parts of the website.</p>
<p>Create multiple navigation configurations so that users have easy access to the content that is the next logical step in their path around the design. While some elements might overlap, others assist users and help them move deeper into the design.</p>
<p>We are in an age where users have come to expect certain levels of personalization. Amazon does a great job of this with navigation elements that even call users by name. Take a close look at the navigation next time you log in to see [Your Name Here]’s Amazon.com. The secondary navigation includes information such as the user’s annual donation for Smile users, recent order history and even credits to other Amazon services. (Everything thereafter is pretty personalized, too.)</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/FvqYVnV.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="5-Order-Nav-Elements-Purposefully"><a href="#5-Order-Nav-Elements-Purposefully" class="headerlink" title="5. Order Nav Elements Purposefully"></a>5. Order Nav Elements Purposefully</h2><p>The order of navigation elements is just as important as the decision to use them. Items at the beginning and end of the navigation element will be most effective, most seen and most clicked. User these positions carefully.</p>
<p>There’s even some science to back this up. The<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Serial_position_effect" target="_blank" rel="external">serial position effect</a>is the tendency of a person to recall the first and last items in a list most consistency. Further, users tend to recall the most recent items best (recency effect) and the first few items in a list are recalled better than middle elements (primacy effect).</p>
<p>Look at user flow patterns in your website analytics to help determine exactly what pages and elements should be front and center. Include pages that users are going to from the homepage and content that you want users to connect with. Eliminate navigation elements that aren’t driving user flow.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/YjyENjZ.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="6-Use-Sticky-Navigation-for-Long-Scrolling-Pages"><a href="#6-Use-Sticky-Navigation-for-Long-Scrolling-Pages" class="headerlink" title="6. Use Sticky Navigation for Long-Scrolling Pages"></a>6. Use Sticky Navigation for Long-Scrolling Pages</h2><p>Don’t let users lose track of navigation. Whether it sticks to the top, or bottom or side of the screen, any page with a long-scrolling format should include a sticky menu. The reason behind this is simple: Don’t make users work to keep interacting with your website.</p>
<p>The easier it is to move around and experience content, the more likely users are to do just that. The more time a user spends on your website with your design, the more likely they are to convert on a desired user action.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/IJrE7nz.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="7-Don’t-Hide-the-Navigation"><a href="#7-Don’t-Hide-the-Navigation" class="headerlink" title="7. Don’t Hide the Navigation"></a>7. Don’t Hide the Navigation</h2><p>Tiny menu items, links tucked away at the bottom of the screen or only in the footer, and pop-out navigation hidden behind oddball icons and lack of navigation on interior pages will only keep users from clicking. Don’t hide website navigation. It should be front and center. It should be on every page.</p>
<p>Users can get to your website in any number of ways. Make sure that there’s a navigational element waiting form them when they arrive.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/IfErIz7.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="8-Use-Descriptive-Labels"><a href="#8-Use-Descriptive-Labels" class="headerlink" title="8. Use Descriptive Labels"></a>8. Use Descriptive Labels</h2><p>From navigation words to icons, every element should tell users exactly what will happen with a click. Use commonly accepted icons, such as a shopping card to check out or magnifying glass for search or even a hamburger icon for pop-out menu styles.</p>
<p>Then take it a step further and use text labels that tell the user exactly what information is contained therein. Try to avoid overly generic labels such as services or offerings, if there’s a word that better explains the content.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/Vn6fumA.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="9-Consider-Full-Page-Nav"><a href="#9-Consider-Full-Page-Nav" class="headerlink" title="9. Consider Full-Page Nav"></a>9. Consider Full-Page Nav</h2><p>Sometimes the design is the navigation. If there are a few key elements that are vital for users, showcase them with full-screen navigation.</p>
<p>While this won’t be appropriate for every project, it can be effective for smaller websites, portfolios or project work.</p>
<p><img src="http://img0.tuicool.com/JN7ry22.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="10-Go-Vertical"><a href="#10-Go-Vertical" class="headerlink" title="10. Go Vertical"></a>10. Go Vertical</h2><p><a href="https://www.webdesignerdepot.com/2017/06/10-sites-doing-vertical-navigation-right/" target="_blank" rel="external">Vertical navigation is trendy right now</a>, and for good reason. It is easy to see and draws the eye because it is somewhat different.</p>
<p>Side, vertically-oriented navigation is a good option for websites that need a little more space for number of navigation elements. With a deeper menu, the design can accommodate more nav elements without feeling cluttered and maintaining adequate space between elements.</p>
<p><img src="http://img1.tuicool.com/RNV7byY.jpg!web" alt=""></p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.tuicool.com/articles/hit/JRRR7za" target="_blank" rel="external">https://www.webdesignerdepot.com/2017/06/10-ways-to-design-menus-that</a>  </p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;There are definite right and wrong ways to design navigation menus. This basic part of a website is often overlooked in the design proces
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
