<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Gmagon Software Official Website - Fast, simple &amp; powerful solutions for everyone.</title>
  <subtitle>Gmagon Software Official Website - Fast, simple &amp; powerful solutions for everyone and more. Visit the site to learn, buy, and get support.</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://gmagon.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-06-02T07:08:00.020Z</updated>
  <id>https://gmagon.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Gmagon Inc</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Men&#39;s Deep Voice</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/02/men-s-deep-voice/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/06/02/men-s-deep-voice/</id>
    <published>2017-06-02T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-02T07:08:00.020Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="How-do-you-enjoy-your-spare-time"><a href="#How-do-you-enjoy-your-spare-time" class="headerlink" title="How do you  enjoy your spare time ?"></a><strong>How do you  enjoy your spare time ?</strong></h3><ul>
<li>Listening music; Reading books,</li>
<li>Watching movies; Shopping,</li>
<li>Drinking coffee with some of your friends or any thing else.</li>
</ul>
<p>I have a strange hobby that I like be surrounded by voices when I am alone, by the way I am now with headphone in my ears intoxicated with Benedict Cumberbatch’ s voice. I’m mad about his deep, low-pitched voice.</p>
<p>Hearing his low, husky voice,  it is charming and may have a gravitational attraction, I want to move closer to him. Imaging his evil &amp; handsome face while holding a obstinate unruly smile. <strong>Oh, I love it</strong></p>
<p><img src="3a83e4e9acffd78281f0f75d1acf3c7a.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h3 id="It-is-amazing-that-most-of-my-girlfriends-like-men’s-deep-voices"><a href="#It-is-amazing-that-most-of-my-girlfriends-like-men’s-deep-voices" class="headerlink" title="It is amazing that most of my girlfriends like men’s deep voices."></a><strong>It is amazing that most of my girlfriends like men’s deep voices.</strong></h3><p>We love it, and just instantly find ourselves having a huge crush on men with deep voices. No idea how that happens, but it just does.</p>
<p><img src="17-cumberbatch-2.w1200.h800.jpg" alt=""></p>
<ul>
<li>The moment when the men enter a room and start talking. Just want to “beg” he to talk        more. we’ re all ears.</li>
<li>They sometimes come across intimidating, and in some cases that can be really attractive.</li>
<li>Their voice speaks volumes about their confidence and powerful. Who doesn’t like             confident men?<br><img src="QS_143562c43c3e4b198b1b346238af632f.png" alt=""></li>
<li>Their voice also sounds comforting. They come across as someone who will protect us.</li>
<li>Men with deep voices also somehow know how to take charge of the situation. And women do     love men who are good decision makers and can take control over situations.</li>
<li>Lastly, they simply sound sexy All.</li>
</ul>
<p>Haha , do you have the same feelings ? <strong>Just enjoy…</strong></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h3 id=&quot;How-do-you-enjoy-your-spare-time&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#How-do-you-enjoy-your-spare-time&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;How do you  enjoy your spare
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tape Rewind</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/05/27/tape-rewind/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/05/27/tape-rewind/</id>
    <published>2017-05-27T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-02T07:04:47.881Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="tumblr_inline_oqgbku5CfS1um1hre_540.jpg" alt=""></p>

<audio id="audio-player" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/gmagonshare/video/upload/v1496219810/Colbie_Caillat_-_Try_v0sobx.mp3" type="audio/mp3" controls="controls" autoplay="autoplay"></audio>

<p><strong>On rainy day</strong><br><strong>Finding a  quiet place.</strong><br><strong>With  A cop of coffee; A book; A song  </strong><br><strong>Recalling the past, thinking about the future.</strong><br><strong>Yesterday, Today, Tomorrow.</strong><br><strong>Day after day.</strong><br><strong>A history of recurrent after another.</strong></p>
<p>I am the one who like recalling, one of my friends said when you began to recall, it means you are old…Maybe, ha ha…</p>
<p>When it comes to memory, you may notice that I have mentioned Walk Man in my previous essay,  but can’t find it for a long time, then began to search in internet , find an interesting video “KIDS REACT TO WALKMAN (Portable Cassette Players)”</p>

<iframe class="post-item-video" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uk_vV-JRZ6E" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p><strong>Below the video , I notice some interesting comments ：</strong></p>
<p><em>1.Considering most of children in the video were born in the 2000’s, they should’ve seen VCRs and VHS tapes and cassette players.﻿ What a sad thing it is .</em></p>
<p><em>2.I’m only 12, but I think old technology is so cool. Without it, there would be no iPhones, iPads, laptops, or anything like that. All of these things like cassette tapes started all of this. I think more people need to appreciate things like this. I’m not hating, I’m just saying people need to appreciate this.﻿</em></p>
<p><em>3.Don’t feel sorry for us growing up in the 90’s ( Also for me in 80’s ). I feel sorry for kids growing up now, everything is to easy today. I still prefer my old NES with the original Super Mario and Zelda over today’s ps3/4 and those new call of duty games… Growing up in the 90’s was one of the greatest thing I can imagine!﻿</em></p>
<p>After seeing these , my memory turns back to the time when I am in school, I remember that every classmate carried Walk Man in their backpack everyday,  every night we have to charge the batteries,(or it will be power off) ,then next day equipped Walk Man with them, put a tape which has nice songs into Walk Man , listened the songs , if you want to listen the song twice , you can rewind the tape; Years later we had MP3 , it is more convenient, we can charge the MP3 directly,  download music in the Internet ,and can listen to a song recycling many times …</p>
<p>In this rainy day, listening the song “Try “again and again…<br>I love the feelings that headphone in my ears with beautiful sounds. <strong>Just enjoy…</strong></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;tumblr_inline_oqgbku5CfS1um1hre_540.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio id=&quot;audio-player&quot; src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/gmagonshare/vide
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Hero In Your Heart</title>
    <link href="https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/05/27/a-hero-in-your-heart/"/>
    <id>https://gmagon.com/blog/2017/05/27/a-hero-in-your-heart/</id>
    <published>2017-05-27T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-02T07:05:36.970Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="tumblr_inline_oqdwxuhPEC1um1hre_540.jpg" alt=""></p>

<audio id="audio-player" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/gmagonshare/video/upload/v1496219822/Hero_-_Mariah_Carey_Lyrics_ahqwdi.mp3" type="audio/mp3" controls="controls" autoplay="autoplay"></audio>

<p><strong> Headphones in my ears with a beautiful song Hero… </strong></p>
<p>I enjoy the melody and the lyrics:</p>
<p><em>“There’s a hero, if you look inside your heart,</em></p>
<p><em>you don’t have to be afraid of what you are.</em></p>
<p><em>There’s an answer. If you reach into your soul.</em></p>
<p><em>And the sorrow that you know, will melt away…”</em></p>
<p><strong> I once saw a saying in a blog “you may not fancy a certain singer, but you must like listening music, because some melodies or lyrics show things for the occasion you like, or both of the two.” </strong></p>
<p>I enjoy wearing my headphone and listening music in my sad or happy time. Even when I am running, walking, reading, or sleeping in bed, I indulge myself in a musical world and cannot take my headphone off. Do you have a moment that a lot of memories appear in your mind, you just want to spend time with your favorite music.</p>
<p><strong> Everyone has a dream, and has been working hard to realize this dream. </strong></p>
<p>After graduation from my university, I left my hometown to a strange city in the first time, and lived in unfamiliar environment, because I just wanted to achieve career success. While facing the pressure of work, I only wanted to go home, even gave up. <strong> On such occasion, I always took out my tiny Walk Man, put headphones in my ears and enjoyed my favorite song-Hero by Mariah Carey. </strong> The song always has the magic power that helps me go through troubled water. Finally, I insisted on the work, and witnessed my growth.</p>
<p>The Hero is a powerful song that can go into your heart, even go into your soul, you can get the answer, all the doubts are gone, a strong hero will stand out. With no fear, I believe that I can insist. When I feel with no hope, get into my deep heart, be strong, be powerful. Finally, you will find you are the hero.</p>
<p><strong> We all know that it is very difficult in the process of realizing a dream, but no one can crush your own dream, don’t give up, tomorrow you will find your way. </strong></p>
<p>I have special emotion to all the songs in my Sony Walk Man. Hero is just one of them.</p>
<p>When I am sad, play the happy songs, when I am thinking, play the soft ones, <strong> just enjoy… </strong></p>

<iframe class="post-item-video" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0IA3ZvCkRkQ?list=RD0IA3ZvCkRkQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;tumblr_inline_oqdwxuhPEC1um1hre_540.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio id=&quot;audio-player&quot; src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/gmagonshare/vide
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
